<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shreyas Ragavan on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shreyas Ragavan on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ESS for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;RStudio is a formidable IDE to work with and offers an environment to seamlessly work with multiple languages beyond R. It is especially convenient for tasks involving frequent visualisation of data frames and plots, and for use with Shiny app development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the text (i.e code) editing capabalities are still significantly lacking compared to the likes of Emacs and Vim. Besides this, it does not offer a seamless interface integrating task, time management and multi-language programming environments to the extent available within Org-mode via Emacs. Enter ESS !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an evolving document of how I use ESS  and will be a useful guide to anybody starting out with ESS especially for R based workflows. My ESS configuration is mostly available in my Dotemacs documentation. However this is a deeper dive into ESS workflows for data science projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emacs Speaks Statistics (ESS) is an add-on package for GNU Emacs. It is designed to support editing of scripts and interaction with various statistical analysis programs such as R, S-Plus, SAS, Stata and OpenBUGS/JAGS. Although all users of these statistical analysis programs are welcome to apply ESS, advanced users or professionals who regularly work with text-based statistical analysis scripts, with various statistical languages/programs, or with different operating systems might benefit from it the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rationale for developing ESS is that most statistical analysis systems provide a more or less sophisticated graphical user interface (GUI). However, their full power is only available using their scripting language. Furthermore, complex statistical analysis projects require a high degree of automation and documentation which can only be handled by creating statistical analysis scripts. Unfortunately, many statistics packages provide only weak text editor functionality and show major differences between them. Without a unified text editor user interface additional effort is required from the user to cope with limited functionality and with text editor differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ess.r-project.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESS website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ess.r-project.org/index.php?Section=documentation&amp;amp;subSection=manuals&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Different versions of the ESS manual&lt;/a&gt; are available online and it is worth a frequent read to aid familiarisation with the commands and features available. The ESS mailing list is also worth subscribing to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it seems that ESS is reasonably popular, it was surprising to find relatively few examples of configurations on the web. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/EmacsSpeaksStatistics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emacs ESS wikipage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://emacs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/ess%5F%5Femacs%5Fspeaks%5Fstatistics.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yi Tang&amp;rsquo;s Emacs configuration&lt;/a&gt; are among the few useful resources I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-a-new-project&#34;&gt;Starting a new project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, I start with a fresh Org-mode document for a new project in a repository of its own. This is as easy as &lt;code&gt;M-x nb-new&lt;/code&gt; in Scimax. This initialises a new git repository in the designated projects folder. Currently, I have each such project as a submodule of the main project repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may seem convenient to include libraries and a variety of other customisations in the .Rrofile startup. However, as mentioned in the initial comments of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1189759/expert-r-users-whats-in-your-rprofile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SO Discussion&lt;/a&gt;, in the interest of reproducibility - it is better to have a script run commands at the beginning of each session. Alternately, one could use a package like YASnippet to insert snippets of frequently used code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;org-documents-for-literate-programming&#34;&gt;Org documents for literate programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a fan of literate programming, my code is usually embedded into Org-babel source blocks in line with the explanations or analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For longer projects, I often define a Yasnippet extension for the source code blocks specifying a unique session name to cater to that project. This prevents mixing up of variables and environments between projects as I switch, and I can search and insert snippets with the handy &lt;code&gt;ivy-yasnippet&lt;/code&gt; package that allows previews of snippets before insertion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, I enter the major mode from the Org-Babel source block (&lt;code&gt;C-c &#39;&lt;/code&gt; inside a source block) to enable access to mode specific features like command completion, variable access and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that when entering a major mode from a source block, the correct or desired ESS process has to be attached, especially if you are simultaneously using multiple sessions. This can be done with the &lt;code&gt;C-c C-s&lt;/code&gt; command after entering the major mode buffer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;frequently-used-ess-commands&#34;&gt;Frequently used ESS commands&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though there are many commands available - the ones listed below are worth noting. Going through the ESS manual is definitely worth the effort to understand detailed descriptions of these commands. Another simple way to search for commands within ESS is using the &lt;code&gt;M-x&lt;/code&gt; command and type in &amp;lsquo;ess&amp;rsquo; to view the commands available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;M-p&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;M-n&lt;/code&gt; : Previous and next command in comint input history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;M-r&lt;/code&gt;      : Regex search of input history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-c C-x&lt;/code&gt;  : List of objects in the environment. Prepend &lt;code&gt;C-u&lt;/code&gt; to print to console. Note that it is possible to list commands of libraries by prepending numbers to &lt;code&gt;C-c C-x&lt;/code&gt;. The default prefix is the global environment, which is a prefix of 1, i.e &lt;code&gt;C-1 C-c C-x&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-c C-v&lt;/code&gt;  : Help at point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-c C-q&lt;/code&gt;  : Ess-quit. This is important to use when exiting an R session. Using this makes sure that temporary buffers are quit. Such buffers can pile up very easily as you use the help documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-c C-z&lt;/code&gt;  : Switch between the R script and the process buffer. This is a nifty feature especially when when using&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-M-x&lt;/code&gt;    : Sends the current selected region or function or paragraph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-c C-d v&lt;/code&gt;: (ess-display-vignettes) this is a handy method to browse all the available vignettes. This opens up a buffer, which contains links to vignettes in multiple formats (PDF, Rmd, Rnw). Note that the vignettes of a newsly installed package is loaded only after being loaded with the library function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-e w&lt;/code&gt; : Resizing the display to adapt to a buffer that has changed dimension. i.e if I split the R terminal buffer which changes it&amp;rsquo;s size - this command will enable the output to be better adjusted to the buffer size and thus enable better readability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;window-configuration&#34;&gt;Window configuration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ESS manual has a helpful snippet if you prefer your window arrangement similar to Rstudio&amp;rsquo;s, which is quite sensible as such. The width values can be modified as required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-emacs-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;emacs-lisp&#34;&gt;(setq display-buffer-alist
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;((&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;*R Dired&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
         (display-buffer-reuse-window display-buffer-in-side-window)
         (side &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; right)
         (slot &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;-1&lt;/span&gt;)
         (window-width &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0.33&lt;/span&gt;)
         (reusable-frames &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;))
        (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;*R&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
         (display-buffer-reuse-window display-buffer-at-bottom)
         (window-width &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0.35&lt;/span&gt;)
         (reusable-frames &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;))
        (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;*Help&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
         (display-buffer-reuse-window display-buffer-in-side-window)
         (side &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; right)
         (slot &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;)
         (window-width &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0.33&lt;/span&gt;)
         (reusable-frames &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;))))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rmarkdown-polymode&#34;&gt;Rmarkdown : Polymode&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polymode makes it easy to work with Rmd, Rnw, Snw format documents within Emacs. The only configuration necessary for this Is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-emacs-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;emacs-lisp&#34;&gt;(require &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;poly-markdown&lt;/span&gt;)
(require &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;poly-R&lt;/span&gt;)

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; MARKDOWN&lt;/span&gt;
(add-to-list &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;auto-mode-alist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;\\.md&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; poly-markdown-mode))

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; R modes&lt;/span&gt;
(add-to-list &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;auto-mode-alist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;\\.Snw&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; poly-noweb+r-mode))
(add-to-list &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;auto-mode-alist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;\\.Rnw&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; poly-noweb+r-mode))
(add-to-list &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;auto-mode-alist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;\\.Rmd&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; poly-markdown+r-mode))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exporting&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;org-todo todo TODO&#34;&gt;TODO&lt;/span&gt; Exporting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When sharing documents, it is necessary to convert to a format non-Emacs users can user. My current approach is to use &lt;code&gt;ox-ipynb&lt;/code&gt; package to export to as a jupyter notebook, and then the excellent jupytext package to convert to Rmd.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Org-mode configuration for Emacs is liberating</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/d16caa34-c2e2-439b-894f-d95be5708160/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 08:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/d16caa34-c2e2-439b-894f-d95be5708160/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TLDR: &lt;a href=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/docs/sr-config&#34;&gt;Check out the Docs section for my Emacs config in Org-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The literate programming paradigm, as conceived by Donald Knuth, represents a move away from writing programs in the manner and order imposed by the computer, and instead enables programmers to develop programs in the order demanded by the logic and flow of their thoughts. Literate programs are written as an uninterrupted exposition of logic in an ordinary human language, much like the text of an essay, in which macros are included to hide abstractions and traditional source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Literate%5Fprogramming&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article on Literate Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had graduated to using an Org-mode based configuration with vanilla Emacs, until discovering Scimax a few years ago. At this point, it seemed easier to switch back to using elisp script files in multiple files which were loaded in the desired / necessary order. The plan was to use a file for each major &amp;lsquo;concept&amp;rsquo;, for example one file each for hydras, Org-mode, mu4e, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is not difficult to manage multiple script files with the projectile package, it does become cumbersome and inelegant to record notes and thoughts in the comment form along with code. Over time, it also becomes difficult to decide the placement of multi-package functions and snippets. As my configuration has evolved - I&amp;rsquo;ve felt an increasing need to shift back to a literate configuration using Org for Emacs, and also separate the personal parts of my configuration to enable sharing on Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a literate configuration enables a live documentary of my Emacs configuration and also adding meaningful notes and snippets which are directly or indirectly related to configuring Emacs. For example, it is important to have IPython and Jupyter installed for Scimax to work correctly, and I can include notes and working scripts for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are discussions on Emacs init time increasing by using a tangled org file. However, this is atleast partially remedied by including a function to tangle the config file whenever it is saved, and there are other methods &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.holgerschurig.de/en/emacs-efficiently-untangling-elisp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;like the one described by Holger Schurig&lt;/a&gt;, which I intend to try out soon. Personally, I have not found any degrade in Emacs init time via Scimax.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental improvements can lead to significant gains</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/32266f09-c9b9-48ff-9c48-e2348eeda33d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/32266f09-c9b9-48ff-9c48-e2348eeda33d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/a&gt;, I was reflecting that my choice of embracing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; and progressively gaining mastery over it was intimately connected with the philosophy preached in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My efforts initially started out with a craving for a system to quantify and manage my tasks, habits, notes, blog writing, job applications and projects in a custom environment, and to be able to build toolkits of code to perform repetitive tasks. As mentioned in an &lt;a href=&#34;../2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954&#34;&gt;earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt;
, I tried several approaches before settling on Emacs. The idea was to find or create a single system to track everything of importance in my life (with ease and efficiency). This was instead of a fragmented approach of using multiple tools and techniques, for example, Sublime Text / Atom as a text editor and &lt;a href=&#34;https://todoist.com/?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt; as a task management tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with a vanilla configuration of Emacs and painstakingly borrowed (and eventually) modified lisp snippets to implement desired &amp;lsquo;features&amp;rsquo; or behaviors. It was a just a couple of features every week, initially focused on Org mode&amp;rsquo;s behavior alone. That was nearly 3 years ago. As of now, I am able to manage my blog [hugo], view my email [mu4e], browse the web [w3m], seamlessly capture notes / ideas / tasks from (almost) anywhere [Org mode], chat on IRC, build multi-language code notebooks with ease [Org babel]. All the above provide me significant advantages in speed and efficiency which still have plenty of potential to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I certainly appear closer to my goal today.. however, I did not know if it was a pipe dream when I started out. It was often extremely frustrating, right from memorizing the &amp;lsquo;crazy&amp;rsquo; keybindings in Emacs, to struggling with getting a lisp snippet to work as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing Emacs had unexpected rewards as well. For example, the need of synchronizing my notes and Emacs configuration with multiple machines led me to Git. &lt;a href=&#34;https://magit.vc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Magit&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; easily accessible commands and relatively visual interface has been a massive help in getting things done with Git, despite not having any deep technical knowledge of how Git works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey with Emacs is testament that an incremental, compounding improvement over time can ultimately result in significant gains. It is also important to acknowledge that I am standing on the shoulder of giants and the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkitchin/scimax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scimax&lt;/a&gt; is a cornerstone in my toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nteract : An interactive computing environment</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://slides.com/villetuulos/human-centric-machine-learning-infrastructure-qcon-2018/#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slide deck from Netflix&lt;/a&gt;, mentions using Nteract as their programming notebook, and prompted a mini exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://moderndata.plot.ly/nteract-revolutionizing-notebook-experience/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post by Safia Abdalla&lt;/a&gt;, (a maintainer/ developer of Nteract) introduces Nteract as an open source, desktop-based, interactive computing application that was designed to overcome a bunch of limitations in Jupyter Notebook&amp;rsquo;s design philosophy. One key difference (among many others) is the ability to execute code in a variety of languages within a single notebook, and it also appears that that the electron based desktop app should make it easier for beginners to start coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along similar lines, this &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.nteract.io/nteract-building-on-top-of-jupyter-9cfbccdd4c1d&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; is a nice primer to the evolution of Ipython, Jupyter Notebooks and Nteract, from the plain vanilla Python console, which was the starting point. Beyond the illuminating definition that the Jupyter notebook is an &amp;lsquo;establishment of well-defined protocols and formats&amp;rsquo;, and is not just a console or a programming notebook, the blog post provides a deeper insight into how these protocols are implemented and communicate with interpreters or Jupyter kernels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Python/comments/6w1zh3/nteract%5Fvs%5Fjupyter%5Fnotebook/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reddit discussion&lt;/a&gt; has a few interesting pros and cons regarding using nteract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I can see the value of computing notebooks like Jupyter and Nteract, I do think that these do not come close to the functionality and ease that can be achieved with Org mode and Emacs, which have been in existence a lot longer. I was able to intuitively transition to using multiple language code &amp;lsquo;notebooks&amp;rsquo; using Org mode. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11296843&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reddit thread&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lepisma.github.io/2016/11/02/org-babel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; elucidate the advantages of using Babel and Org mode over Jupyter notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage recorded macros to learn elisp and hack together workflows in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/7b7b94ca-2d77-4814-8cae-c9e95d3f8bc4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/7b7b94ca-2d77-4814-8cae-c9e95d3f8bc4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The primary power of Emacs is that you can create customised workflows to suit your needs. However, &lt;code&gt;lisp&lt;/code&gt; is probably not a language that many learn as a typical requirement in the academic systems, perhaps even for a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would one then start customisting Emacs? One way would be to hunt for snippets from forums like reddit and stack overflow, and customise them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another easy way to learn a programming language, especially one that is intrinsic to a software is to record macros and edit these macros. Emacs is no different in this regard, and in fact makes it easy being a self-documenting text editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Silex/elmacro&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The elmacro package&lt;/a&gt; reduces some of the burden. The recorded macro does require a subsequent clean-up to be useful, which is still easier than coding lisp from scratch. In any case, exploring the recorded code will eventuall lead towards proficiency in writing lisp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://emacsnotes.wordpress.com/2018/11/15/elmacro-write-emacs-lisp-snippet-even-when-you-arent-a-programmer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This blog post&lt;/a&gt; provides a more detailed introduction, including creating a menu entry for elmacro. As highlighted by the blog, some commands do not register in Emacs, since external packages handle those functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, I have 3 main repositories where I commit my work. This is a frequent, repetitive process that is often done till (and at) the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are snippets that were developed leveraging elmacro:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; Maximise current frame, open scimax user directory,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; call magit, switch window and open the scimax directory&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; Scimax magit status and dired&lt;/span&gt;
(defun sr/windows-magit-scimax ()
  (interactive)
  (ace-delete-other-windows)
  (dired &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/scimax/user/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
  (switch-window-then-split-right &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;)
  (magit-status &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/scimax/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
  (switch-window)
  (split-window-vertically)
  (dired-up-directory)
  (windmove-right)
  )

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; Maximise current frame, open org directory, call magit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; my_org magit status&lt;/span&gt;
(defun sr/windows-magit-org ()
  (interactive)
  (ace-delete-other-windows)
  (magit-status &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/my_org/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
  )

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; Maximise current frame, call magit for my_projects directory&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; split buffer and call dired in case I need to navigate to a particular directory.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; the latter can also be done via magit itself if desired.&lt;/span&gt;
(defun sr/windows-magit-projects ()
  (interactive)
  (ace-delete-other-windows)
  (switch-window-then-split-right &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;)
  (magit-status &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/my_projects/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
  (switch-window)
  (dired &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/my_projects/&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
  (switch-window)
  )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another more complicated example, is using projectile to switch to a project, call a particular file in the project and then split the buffer and open the tasks of that particular project with a narrowed view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I capture each project&amp;rsquo;s tasks and notes separately in an org file &lt;a href=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/post/8f702ce2-8bb7-40a3-b44b-a47222c02909/&#34;&gt;using org-projectile&lt;/a&gt;. This is useful especially for coding projects so that the code is better separated from notes and yet linked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; This is to rapidly switch between projects and have a similar window configuration,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; i.e. a main file, and a narrowed view of the tasks heading.&lt;/span&gt;

(defun sr/windows-projects ()
  (interactive)
  (ace-delete-other-windows)
  (switch-window-then-split-right &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;)
  (projectile-switch-project)
  (switch-window)
  (find-file &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/my_org/project-tasks.org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
  (widen)
  (helm-org-rifle-current-buffer)
  (org-narrow-to-subtree)
  (outline-show-children)
  )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are not perfect. For example, I&amp;rsquo;d rather have to select the project name only once and have that feed into &lt;code&gt;helm-org-rifle&lt;/code&gt;. These are topics of future exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What then remained was being able call these functions with a few keypresses. Hydras enable this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;(defhydra sr/process-window-keys ()
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;Key^^   ^Workflow^
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;--------------------
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;o       org magit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;s       scimax magit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;p       projects magit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;w       select project and set window config
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;SPC     exit
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
  (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;o&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; sr/windows-magit-org )
  (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;p&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; sr/windows-magit-projects )
  (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;s&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; sr/windows-magit-scimax )
  (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;w&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; sr/windows-projects)
  (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;SPC&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt;)
  )

(global-set-key (kbd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;lt;f8&amp;gt; m&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;sr/process-window-keys/body&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the above in place, now all I have to do is call the menu to choose the desired function by typing &lt;code&gt;F8&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;m&lt;/code&gt; and then type &lt;code&gt;o&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; and so on. The hydra exits with &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;, which makes it easy to switch to another project in case there is nothing to commit in the current choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though simple and in many ways primitive - these functions have still saved me a lot of repetitive acrobatics on my keyboard and I enjoy using Them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical notes : Research paper on learning/teaching data science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Title: Navigating Diverse Data Science Learning: Critical Reflections Towards Future Practice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Yehia Elkhatib&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1807.03750v1.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This are my notes on the above paper, which mainly deals with detailing the methods explored and implemented to impart a high quality of education in data science. The paper also provides an interesting breakup of the different roles in data science workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The importance of being able to work in a team is highlighted. Working in isolation for a data scientist almost renders the results meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering the typically diverse backgrounds of DS practitioners, it is difficult to devise a curriculum that caters to everybody. This factor is certainly critical to consider before taking up any formal university courses. I would not want to spend a great deal of time and money in learning obsolete techniques or technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are differences in learning rates based on the background, and past academic environments. In particular, most students do not seem to realize that the best learning takes place in a &amp;lsquo;social&amp;rsquo; manner. Besides addressing the above, several aspects of effective learning and aligning the curriculum and teaching methodology to the typical industrial workflows are explored in this paper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The literature references of past studies and research would certainly make interesting reads. However, they are more relevant to those in the teaching line. An interesting approach would be to read between the lines to extract the best practices for students to learn rapidly and effectively. However, there are many direct resources and techniques to approach the latter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;DS Roles :- Core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Janitor&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data cleaning, pre-processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scout&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EDA, early insights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analyst&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifying patterns, initial hypothesis, evidence of unforeseen narratives)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Builder&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automate decision making, ML, DL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curator&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;storage formats across interfaces, data governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engineer&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage the interface between development and production products, efficiency and reliability of data interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Auxiliary roles : these roles come into the picture as the DS team grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domain specialist&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data significance, sources of bias&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure manager&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;support to build and operate, beyond the data engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicator&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicating explanatory and confirmatory analyses, setting up systems to interact with the audiences outside the DS team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facilitator&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A/B experiments, additional support to the communicator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why bother with Emacs and workflows?</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/11ef85e6-9efc-4af4-b5f3-7648f9ee9308/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 12:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/11ef85e6-9efc-4af4-b5f3-7648f9ee9308/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/categories/emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;several posts&lt;/a&gt; on different ways and tools available to aid productivity, and probably a lot about Emacs. My background is in computational physics, and not in programming, and yet Emacs has been an indispensable driver of my daily workflow for the past 3 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is that knowing Emacs (or Vim), or having a custom configuration is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/9ghpb4/was%5Fanyone%5Fever%5Fimpressed%5Fby%5Fyour%5Femacs%5Fskills/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;not a wildly marketable skill&lt;/a&gt;, nor is it mandatory to achieve spectacular results. An Emacs configuration suits personal workflows and style, which may be borderline peculiar to another person. Such a dependence on customised tools would also drastically reduces your speed while using a new IDE or text editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So : why add Emacs to the ever-growing to-do list? The question is more pertinent considering that mastery of a &amp;lsquo;text editor&amp;rsquo; is not something you can freely talk about and frequently expect empathetic responses or even a spark like connection. Emacs would be considered by many to be an esoteric and archaic software with a steep learning curve that is not beginner friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However &amp;hellip;..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.fugue.co/2015-11-11-guide-to-emacs.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; elucidates many points where Emacs can help PHB&amp;rsquo;s (Pointy Haired Boss). The internet abounds with &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11386590&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=6094610&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;examples&lt;/a&gt; on how org-mode and Emacs have changed lives for the better. Here is another &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/new-window-manager.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cool article by Howard Abrams&lt;/a&gt; on using Emacs as his (only) window manager, in place of a desktop environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching an experienced person handle his tools emphasises the potential art form behind it, especially when compared to the bumbling of an amateur. Yes, the amateur may get the job done given enough time, and depending on his capabilities - even match the experienced professional&amp;rsquo;s output (eventually).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as experience is gained, the workflows and steps to achieve an optimal result become more lucid. I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced an exponentially increasing and compelling need to implement specific preferences to achieve the required optimized results faster and with fewer mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is therefore obvious that the workflow and tools used must allow the provision to evolve, customise and automate. This is particularly true with respect to the world of data science and programming. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is anything better than Emacs with respect to customisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;having a combination of scripts or snippets in different languages to jumpstart a project, which is available with a few keypresses? (Yasnippet)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintaining a blog with a single document, with articles updated automatically on a status change. (ox-hugo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working with multiple R environments in a single document. (Org-babel, ESS)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different Window configurations and processes for different projects that can be called with a few keypresses (hint : keyboard macros)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An integrated git porcelain that can actually help you learn git so much faster (magit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intimately integrating email with tasks, projects, documentation and workflows (mu4e, Org-mode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A customised text editor available right in your terminal (Use Emacsclient launched off a daemon within a terminal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not requiring to use the mouse for navigation!&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now : imagine the consolidated effect of having all the above at your disposal, in a reasonably streamlined state. Then, considering the cumulative effect over multiple projects! The above is just a shallow overview of the possibilities with Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investing in learning Emacs, has the serious potential to spawn exponential results in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;Articles on using Yasnippet: &amp;mdash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.refu.co/?p=1355&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using Emacs Yasnippet against repetitive boileplate code&lt;/a&gt; || &lt;a href=&#34;https://jpace.wordpress.com/2012/10/20/tweaking-emacs-snippets/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tweaking Emacs Yasnippet&lt;/a&gt; || &lt;a href=&#34;https://joaotavora.github.io/yasnippet/snippet-expansion.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Expanding snippets&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;Links to using R with Emacs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.r-bloggers.com/using-r-with-emacs-and-ess/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using R with Emacs and ESS&lt;/a&gt; || &lt;a href=&#34;https://lucidmanager.org/using-r-with-emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using R with Emacs&lt;/a&gt; || &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/8gr6jt/looking%5Ffor%5Ftips%5Ffrom%5Fr%5Fcoders%5Fwho%5Fuse%5Fess/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tips from R Coders who use ESS&lt;/a&gt; || &lt;a href=&#34;https://thescientificshrimper.wordpress.com/2018/12/12/soapbox-rant-why-i-use-emacs-for-r-programming/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why I use Emacs for R programming&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;See this &lt;a href=&#34;http://rss.slashdot.org/~r/Slashdot/slashdot/~3/7iykh9HdS5U/i-stopped-using-a-computer-mouse-for-a-week-and-it-was-amazing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;article of a non-technical user&amp;rsquo;s experiment&lt;/a&gt; with not using the mouse, reporting significant gains in speed and productivity. I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced this myself after gaining basic proficiency in moving around Emacs.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly accessing cheatsheets to learn data science with Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://university.business-science.io/p/ds4b-101-r-business-analysis-r&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Matt Dancho&amp;rsquo;s course DSB-101-R&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome course to step into ROI driven business analytics fueled by Data Science. In this course, among many other things - he teaches methods to understand and use cheatsheets to gain rapid &lt;em&gt;level-ups&lt;/em&gt;, especially to find information connecting various packages and functions and workflows. I have been hooked to this approach and needed a way to quickly refer to the different cheatsheets as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FavioVazquez/ds-cheatsheets&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Favio Vazquez&amp;rsquo;s ds-cheatsheets repo&lt;/a&gt;, akin to the One Ring to Rule them All (with respect to Cheatsheets of course), combined with Emacs (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bbatsov/projectile&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Projectile&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/emacs-helm/helm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Helm&lt;/a&gt; packages) make it almost a breeze to find a specific cheatsheet quickly, by just typing in a few words.&amp;nbsp;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The built-in Hydras in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkitchin/scimax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scimax&lt;/a&gt; make it very easy to do the above with a few key presses. All I do is &lt;code&gt;F12&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; p &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ww, start typing in &amp;ldquo;ds-&amp;rdquo; and choose the project and then start typing in the name of the PDF file I&amp;rsquo;m looking for. Check out the animation below.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/Emacs-projectile-cheatsheet.gif&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Rapidly switching to a cheatsheet PDF&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above concept applies to switching to any file in any git based project that is added to Projectile&amp;rsquo;s lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next aspect to consider was switching between maximized buffer of the opened cheatsheet PDF and the current code buffer. As it goes in Emacs, &amp;ldquo;there&amp;rsquo;s probably a package for that..&amp;rdquo; ! My solution was to use one of the various frame/window configuration packages in Emacs to save the position and orientation of the buffers and rapidly switch between the maximised PDF frame and the split code and interpreter frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitating the above was in fact already available in Scimax, where a frame or window configuration can be saved into a register that is valid for that session. Persistent saving of window configuration across sessions (i.e Emacs restarts) is a little more complex, but it is still possible with some tweaking. Winner-mode is also an interesting option to switch rapidly between window configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;To some extent, it is also possible that launchers like the Alfred app could be set or programmed to search in particular locations. This is a less &lt;em&gt;hacky&lt;/em&gt; and still a functional option for Mac users.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to RSS</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:51:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-rss&#34;&gt;Why use RSS?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off late, I had been relying more on email based content consumption. The phenomenally fast search and filtering capabilities that can be leveraged with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mu4e&lt;/a&gt; make this easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with all these filters, it is quite difficult to keep on top of news and information from different sources. It is actually inconvenient to mix important emails and correspondence with newsletters and the like, which arrive by the dozen(s) everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a nagging feeling that relevant and &amp;lsquo;up to date&amp;rsquo; information is better searched through Google, with a fresh search each time. This approach invites distractions. One remedy is to link a google news feed of a search term into your RSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;, however, the exploration made me actually realise that a dedicated RSS reader could inspire focused reading and aid in retention of information, and could be a better option than flooding my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An all-in-one solution for reading RSS feeds with a capable in-built browser to view images/webpages/videos would be excellent, along with the ability to sync with multiple services and facilitate capturing notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploration&#34;&gt;Exploration:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within Emacs - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skeeto/elfeed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elfeed&lt;/a&gt; (along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/algernon/elfeed-goodies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elfeed-goodies&lt;/a&gt;) is a good option to read feeds and is strongly integrated with Emacs and org-mode. A single keypress can be programmed to store a link as an org-heading with a note. This would really be my first choice as I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to work rather well. I can use an org file to easily organise my feeds !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there seems no easy way to sync completed feeds to my iOS devices, though &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/areina/elfeed-cljsrn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;solutions exist for Android&lt;/a&gt;. I do spend a lot of time on my computer, however, it seems I can just read better and faster on my iPad and therefore a sync to mobile devices is still important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it does not seem to be a mainstream recommendation on reviews like &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-rss-reader-os-x/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the sweet setup&lt;/a&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vienna-rss.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt; is a reliable solution (open source!) to consider using to browse RSS feeds on the Mac OS. This comes with a caveat - some tinkering is required to get it to sync with a service.Vienna has inbuilt share options to share via Buffer or Twitter. Side note: I would recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;https://buffer.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt; to manage posts on multiple social media sites in a seamless manner. Buffer&amp;rsquo;s free tier should be sufficient for moderate, personal purposes. I use it to post on Twitter and Linked in simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;harvesting-information&#34;&gt;Harvesting information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next consideration was harvesting notable information of interest from the RSS feeds. If not Emacs, the information has to go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.devontechnologies.com/products/devonthink/overview.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DEVONThink Pro&lt;/a&gt; (DTP), which has a handy pull out drawer into which content can be dragged. I was able to just drag and drop the article or text selection into the DTP drawer. This appears as a URL / bookmark in DTP, and can be converted to a formatted note or web archive subsequently. A script could probably accomplish this automatically. That&amp;rsquo;s for a future project.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/vienna-dtp-drawer.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Screenshot - Vienna + DTP drawer&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, an application external to Emacs (especially without a customisable keyboard driven flow) is not the desirable way to do things. Most websites usually have an RSS feed or email subscription possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opting-for-feedly-as-a-susbcription-service-and-rss-app&#34;&gt;Opting for Feedly as a susbcription service and RSS app&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Vienna had to be abandoned as it felt more sensible to opt for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; subscription to enable a seamless mobile experience. The Feedly app turned out to run surprisingly well on my ancient iPad and I can still drag and drop entire articles into DTP which come out to be formatted RTFD files which could be read and highlighted in leisure. While it may be nice to opt for a standalone app in the Mac for RSS feeds, the Feedly app satisfies my needs and is also available cross-platform. Note: I use the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goldenhillsoftware.com/unread/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Unread app&lt;/a&gt; to read RSS on my newer iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the numerous sync options, &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; provides other interesting features in their pro subscription, like setting up Google keyword searching and organising multiple feeds into &amp;lsquo;boards&amp;rsquo;. This will certainly help in enabling some level of filtering. The method of organising sources and OPML imports in the mac app is a little clunky and not comfortably intuitive, but it is usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://emacs.stackexchange.com/questions/4138/how-do-i-use-emacs-as-a-feedly-com-client&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;no easy way to use Elfeed as a feedly client&lt;/a&gt; either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-cover-them-all&#34;&gt;How to cover them all?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With numerous sources available on most topics - a technique to read is of even more importance. Besides leveraging custom boards, it seems the best way to consume content is to rapidly sweep through the titles and the short descriptions, and in parallel skim through articles of interest. If the article (even slightly) feels worth recording and reading in detail, I select the entire article and drag it into DTP via the drawer for a future session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to deploy DTP as my primary reading app, because of the ability to highlight lines (which are generally available across devices). Besides aiding in skimming the article in the future, it helps me know I&amp;rsquo;ve actually read the article. This is in addition to the core ability to use DTP&amp;rsquo;s AI algorithms in searching through my notes and forming connections between ideas. I also use smart groups that show me the articles captured in the last 1 week, 2 weeks, 3 weeks, which helps me re-visit them in a structured method. The latter works rather well as a memory aid.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/feedly-dtp-screenshot.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Article captured from Feedly into DTP&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans&#34;&gt;Future plans?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be ideal to setup my own server which will process the RSS feeds. Perhaps a Raspberry Pi or something else could be employed. This would be a cost efficient approach for the long term. Such a setup would enable using Elfeed to source articles from the server and thus sync with my mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I guess I will have to rely on Feedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;It is probably worth noting that Feedly pro has several 3rd party integrations available out of the box including Evernote.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Archaic&#39; text based email clients rock!</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e4e7ebb1-4c0c-41d6-b7e4-1c1c09e48c80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 19:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e4e7ebb1-4c0c-41d6-b7e4-1c1c09e48c80/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;ox-hugo-toc toc&#34;&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tldr-for-the-busy-folks&#34;&gt;TLDR - for the busy folks&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#goals&#34;&gt;Goals:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#summary&#34;&gt;Summary:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#multiple-email-accounts-dot-lack-of-a-unified-interface-dot&#34;&gt;Multiple email accounts. Lack of a unified interface.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#creating-sync-channels-via-mbsync&#34;&gt;Creating sync channels via &lt;code&gt;mbsync&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#text-based-email-client-speed-simplicity&#34;&gt;Text based email client! Speed + simplicity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#why-mu4e-rocks-for-me-the-perks&#34;&gt;Why mu4e rocks [for me] - the perks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#quirks&#34;&gt;Quirks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#multiple-levels-of-filters-are-still-necessary-dot&#34;&gt;Multiple levels of filters are still necessary.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#takeaways&#34;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#links-and-references&#34;&gt;Links and References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!--endtoc--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/myterminal/how-i-unified-my-email-accounts-in-2019-1pji&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dev.to blog post&lt;/a&gt; inspired me to complete this languishing draft of my current email setup, and the benefits I&amp;rsquo;ve gained from using a text based email client in Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you find it entertaining. In any case, the links and reference section will certainly prove useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr-for-the-busy-folks&#34;&gt;TLDR - for the busy folks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goals&#34;&gt;Goals:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unification of email accounts while preserving separate individual components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local backup of email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential to extend system to a personal server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email access from Emacs !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully improve overall productivity with reduced context switching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started with 2 Gmail accounts and 1 MSN account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Switched to a paid account with Fastmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Fastmail&amp;rsquo;s tools to transfer email from both Gmail and MSN accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup forwarding for all new emails from to Fastmail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decided between retaining copies of emails in Gmail/MSN or deleting them once forwarded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used customised settings in mu4e to manage Email from within Emacs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occasionally rely on web browser / iOS app. Fastmail&amp;rsquo;s interface is clean and very fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goals Achieved !! Live with the quirks and enjoy the perks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the &lt;a href=&#34;#links-and-references&#34;&gt;Links and References&lt;/a&gt; section for almost all the resources I relied on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A portion of my mu4e configuration is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/docs/sr-config/#mu4e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on my website&lt;/a&gt;. The personal filters and configuration are placed in an encrypted file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mbsync configuration is posted as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/shrysr/21676fc69d50337d94c5648b9d31f70a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;public gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;multiple-email-accounts-dot-lack-of-a-unified-interface-dot&#34;&gt;Multiple email accounts. Lack of a unified interface.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some years back, I found that I had 2 Gmail accounts, and an MSN account. I
discarded age old Yahoo and rediffmail accounts which were luckily not used much
(and God knows how many more I made as a kid).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gmail&amp;rsquo;s interface felt just about tolerable, but inconvenient. The idea of viewing ads tailored to the content of emails had become disconcerting. Their Inbox app was
interesting, but did not work smooth enough. MSN&amp;rsquo;s web interace and apps always
felt cumbersome, though updates over the years, this has improved significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Useful emails could be email digests that contain a wealth of links,
discussions, articles and information. Or perhaps email digests of product and
technology news that are useful to retain as an archive of reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to be able to process these links in a systematic manner, and
have them available with a fast search system that is also integrated with a task
management system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My solution was to switch to forwarding all my emails to a single Fastmail
account. It&amp;rsquo;s been an excellent experience over 2+ years.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-sync-channels-via-mbsync&#34;&gt;Creating sync channels via &lt;code&gt;mbsync&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mbsync configuration is posted as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/shrysr/21676fc69d50337d94c5648b9d31f70a&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;public gist&lt;/a&gt;. It is reasonably self explanatory, and shows how separate channels were made grouping together folders, by specifying a pattern. This took some time, but was finally very satisfying to know as a fine grained control technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out using offlineimap. I found mbsync to be significantly faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-based-email-client-speed-simplicity&#34;&gt;Text based email client! Speed + simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine being engrossed with your code or engineering notebook and the need for
shooting off an urgent brief email arises. What if this could be done with a few
key-presses on an email client, right from the terminal or the code editor that
you are already engrossed in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about adding an email as a task in your organiser with a deadline / planned date?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I had the option to setup separate channels of mail transfer, such that I can sync the inbox or a custom group of folders alone when I am pressed for bandwidth or space?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practical solutions will need to cater to a lot more situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is: usually anything you need is possible (or already implemented) using Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mu4e&lt;/a&gt;, which uses the indexer mu as it&amp;rsquo;s back-end. There are other popular
options like &lt;a href=&#34;https://notmuchmail.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;notmuch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mutt.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mutt&lt;/a&gt;. I have briefly experimented with mutt, which has
a fast email search capability, but has to be coupled with another front-end to
be used within Emacs or elsewhere. The philosophy and system behind notmuch
(leveraging the Gmail tag based approach) differ from mu4e.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a few years of using this system, I have found that text and terminal based email clients offer a speed and integrity that is extremely pleasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-mu4e-rocks-for-me-the-perks&#34;&gt;Why mu4e rocks [for me] - the perks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to create custom search filters that can be accessed with easy shortcuts. An example to demonstrate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-emacs-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;emacs-lisp&#34;&gt;(setq mu4e-bookmarks
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;( &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;(make-mu4e-bookmark
       :name  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Unread messages&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :query &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;flag:unread AND NOT flag:trashed&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :key &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;?u&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;(make-mu4e-bookmark
       :name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Today&amp;#39;s messages&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :query &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;date:today..now&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :key &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;?t&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;(make-mu4e-bookmark
       :name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Last 7 days&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :query &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;date:7d..now&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :key &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;?w&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;(make-mu4e-bookmark
       :name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Messages with images&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :query &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;mime:image/*&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :key &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;?p&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;(make-mu4e-bookmark
       :name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Finance News&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :query (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;concat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:etnotifications@indiatimes.com OR &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:newsletters@valueresearchonline.net&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:value research&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
       :key &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;?f&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;(make-mu4e-bookmark
       :name &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Science and Technology&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
       :query (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;concat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:googlealerts-noreply@google.com OR &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:reply@email.engineering360.com OR &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:memagazine@asme.org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:action@ifttt.com&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;from:digitaleditions@techbriefs.info&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
       :key &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;?S&lt;/span&gt;)
         ))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how it looks:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/mu4e-start.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Mu4e start page&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete keyboard based control, and using it with Emacs means the ability to
compose email from anywhere and build all kinds of workflows. Examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hit Control+x and m (&lt;code&gt;C-x m&lt;/code&gt;) in Emacs parlance, and I have a
compose window open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are built-in workflows and functions in starter-kits like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkitchin/scimax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scimax&lt;/a&gt;, which enable you to email an org-heading or buffer directly
into an email, with the formatting usually preserved, and as
intended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often use yasnippet to insert links to standard attachments like my
resume. This essentially means being able to attach files with a 1-2 key
strokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Mu4e may be a programmatic solution with no pleasing GUI - it
allows one to search a large number of emails with glorious ease. This
is particularly more effective on a SSD drive, rather than the
conventional Hard disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One has to experience the above to &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; the dramatic impact it makes in getting
closer in speed to your thoughts, using a customisable system.  Emails can be
easily captured or added as tasks into &lt;a href=&#34;https://orgmode.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Org mode&lt;/a&gt; documents as a part of task and
project management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the mu4e and mbsync, I&amp;rsquo;ve devised a &amp;lsquo;sane inbox&amp;rsquo; which is bereft of the
noise, like annoying digests, social media updates and so on.  The idea was to
dedicate focused blocks to rapidly process email, all within Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried using Todoist extensively in the past, along with their integration
with Gmail. This approach is a reasonable solution, if one is open to using
different applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quirks&#34;&gt;Quirks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;mu4e&lt;/code&gt; is a text based email interface. It can be set such that the rendered &lt;code&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt;
is displayed in the mu4e-view buffer for each email, which enables graphics and
pictures (if any). However, the render is not perfect at all times.  The HTML
parsing engine can be specified. Thus, heavy &lt;code&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt; emails are unlikely to
render correctly, to the extent of being a nuisance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such emails can be viewed in the browser of your choice with merely 2 key presses, &amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo; and then &amp;lsquo;v&amp;rsquo;, with cursor in the body of the email. This could be Firefox, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://w3m.sourceforge.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;w3m&lt;/a&gt; or any other browser of your choice.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email syncing frequency is set in mu4e. This update process takes a few seconds, and it is not as seamless as a web app. Notifications for new email can be configured on the mode line or through pop-ups in Emacs. However, the experience with working synced emails is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;multiple-levels-of-filters-are-still-necessary-dot&#34;&gt;Multiple levels of filters are still necessary.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Situations where I do not have access to Emacs will need me to use the iOS app or the web interface. Therefore the inbox in the web interface here cannot be &amp;lsquo;insane&amp;rsquo;. Therefore a higher level of filters are implemented in Fastmail itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example all Linked in group and job updates have their own folders. These
folders are all subfolders of the Archive. They never reach the inbox at
all. These emails often remain unread, or if necessary, I can focus on bunches
of them at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By grouping all such incoming mails into subfolders within the Archive folder, I can use a single channel for all the &lt;em&gt;relatively&lt;/em&gt; unimportant mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;takeaways&#34;&gt;Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using an &amp;lsquo;archaic&amp;rsquo; text based email client (mu4e) has significantly boosted the speed with which I can handle my emails and focus on tasks. The simple interface and speed enables better focus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While there are many articles and plenty of guidance on this topic, it takes time and patience to get this working the way you need it to. However, once it is setup, it does become rather comfortable to use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Context switching is expensive on the brain and dents productivity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Integrating email with time and project management is important. mu4e integrates well with Org mode. Beyond tasks, it is also a good reference, and I can easily attach notes, summaries etc to these emails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;links-and-references&#34;&gt;Links and References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the links and references I&amp;rsquo;ve used in setting up and troubleshooting my email setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These could be organized better, and some links may be repeated. All put together, these should give you all you need to get hooked up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!--quoteend--&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the links have additional comments, and many are tagged with dates, as a reference to when I collected the link. Sometimes, this is fun to reflect on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul class=&#34;task-list&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cachestocaches.com/2017/3/complete-guide-email-emacs-using-mu-and-/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Complete Guide to Email in Emacs using Mu and Mu4e&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2017-03-08 Wed 10:04&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ict4g.net/adolfo/notes/2014/12/27/EmacsIMAP.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reading IMAP Mail in Emacs on OSX | Adolfo Villafiorita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-11-27 Sun 08:17&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;label&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; disabled class=&#34;task-list-item&#34;&gt; Excellent link talking about mu4e and notifications &lt;a href=&#34;https://martinralbrecht.wordpress.com/2016/05/30/handling-email-with-emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Handling Email with Emacs  malb::blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-08-01 Mon 18:37&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/3s5fas/which%5Femail%5Fclient%5Fmu4e%5Fmutt%5Fnotmuch%5Fgnus%5Fdo%5Fyou/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Which email client (mu4e, Mutt, notmuch, Gnus) do you use inside Emacs, and why? : emacs&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-05-31 Tue 07:32&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://emacs-fu.blogspot.in/2012/08/introducing-mu4e-for-email.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;emacs-fu: introducing mu4e, an e-mail client for emacs&lt;/a&gt; - Emacs and mu4e stuff  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-04-20 Wed 13:02&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kirang.in/2014/11/13/emacs-as-email-client-with-offlineimap-and-mu4e-on-osx/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emacs as email client with offlineimap and mu4e on OSX &lt;em&gt;/ KG /&lt;/em&gt; Hacks. Thoughts. Writings.&lt;/a&gt; - nice blog related to Emacs and linux  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-04-21 Thu 22:44&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://writequit.org/eos/eos-mail.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EOS: Mail (Email) Module&lt;/a&gt; - explaining multiple email setup in mu4e  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-04-27 Wed 07:56&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.memoryimprintstudio.com/the-ultimate-emailing-agent-with-mu4e-and-emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Ultimate Emailing Agent with Mu4e and Emacs  Emacs, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Linux and Programming etc&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-08-17 Wed 13:19&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://varunbpatil.github.io/2013/08/19/eom/#.VxXTtM7hXCs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Varun B Patil | EOM a.k.a End of Mail a.k.a Emacs + offlineimap + mu4e&lt;/a&gt; - multiple accounts  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-04-19 Tue 12:19&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pragmaticemacs.com/emacs/master-your-inbox-with-mu4e-and-org-mode/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Master your inbox with mu4e and org-mode | Pragmatic Emacs&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-03-26 Sat 14:56&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notmuch - email setup  &lt;a href=&#34;https://wwwtech.de/articles/2016/jul/my-personal-mail-setup&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;My personal mail setup  Articles  WWWTech&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2017-06-13 Tue 16:09&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kmjn.org/notes/unix%5Fstyle%5Fmail%5Ftools.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Search-oriented tools for Unix-style mail | Mark J. Nelson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2017-05-10 Wed 16:29&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interesting comparison of mu and notmuch, going beyond superficial
differences, but not too much depth either.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lukespear.co.uk/mutt-multiple-accounts-mbsync-notmuch-gpg-and-sub-minute-updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mutt with multiple accounts, mbsync, notmuch, GPG and sub-minute updates | French to English translator&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2017-04-28 Fri 07:19&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interesting link, author profile and content available on-line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bostonenginerd.com/posts/notmuch-of-a-mail-setup-part-2-notmuch-and-emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Assorted Nerdery - Notmuch of a mail setup Part 2 - notmuch andEmacs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2017-04-27 Thu 18:41&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mutt,  mu4e and notmuch links

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/6805783/send-html-page-as-email-using-mutt&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;bash - Send Html page As Email using &amp;ldquo;mutt&amp;rdquo; - Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fiasko-nw.net/~thomas/projects/htmail-view.html.en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reading html email withmutt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xaizek.github.io/2014-07-22/prefer-plain-text-format-over-html-in-mutt/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Prefer plain text format over HTML in mutt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://foivos.zakkak.net/tutorials/using%5Femacs%5Fand%5Fnotmuch%5Fmail%5Fclient.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using emacs and notmuch as a mail client - Foivos . Zakkak . net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/4jqyzu/help%5Fwith%5Fmu4e%5Fmultiple%5Faccounts/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Help with mu4e multiple accounts : emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/3kj6v4/using%5Fmutt%5Fofflineimap%5Fand%5Fnotmuch%5Fto%5Fwrangle/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using Mutt, OfflineIMAP and Notmuch to wrangle your inbox. : linux&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-06-16 Thu 15:23&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Articles/705856/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A year with Notmuch mail {LWN.net}&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2018-04-17 Tue 01:21&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mu4e specific Links  &lt;span class=&#34;timestamp-wrapper&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;timestamp&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;2016-04-19 Tue 21:48&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e/Gmail-configuration.html#Gmail-configuration&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mu4e 0.9.16 user manual: Gmail configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=mu4e+tutorials&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;gws%5Frd=cr&amp;amp;ei=4IwVV5jkC8fd0ATZ3q2gDA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mu4e tutorials - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/3junsg/tutorial%5Femail%5Fin%5Femacs%5Fwith%5Fmu4e%5Fand%5Fimapssl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tutorial: email in Emacs with mu4e and IMAP+SSL : emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pragmaticemacs.com/mu4e-tutorials/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mu4e tutorials | Pragmatic Emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macs.hw.ac.uk/~rs46/posts/2014-01-13-mu4e-email-client.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Drowning in Email; mu4e to the Rescue.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://standardsandfreedom.net/index.php/2014/08/28/mu4e/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emacs &amp;amp; the obsessive email mongerer | Moved by Freedom  Powered by Standards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!topic/mu-discuss/NzQmkK4qo7I&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mu4e + nullmailer - Google Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nullprogram.com/blog/2013/09/03/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Leaving Gmail Behind  null program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=view+html+mails+in+mu4e&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;gws%5Frd=cr&amp;amp;ei=e74VV%5F%5FiOMPM0ASlsq2ACg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;view html mails in mu4e - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e/Reading-messages.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mu4e 0.9.16 user manual: Reading messages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/1xad11/in%5Fmu4e%5Fis%5Fthis%5Fhow%5Fyour%5Fhtmlheavy%5Femails%5Frender/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;In mu4e, is this how your HTML-heavy emails render? : emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://varunbpatil.github.io/2013/08/19/eom/#.VxXTtM7hXCs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Varun B Patil | EOM a.k.a End of Mail a.k.a Emacs + offlineimap + mu4e&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e/Marking-messages.html#Marking-messages&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mu4e 0.9.16 user manual: Marking messages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=change+the+date+column+view+in+mu4e&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;gws%5Frd=cr&amp;amp;ei=TDgWV8zEBIOLuwTXk5uYAw#q=change+the+date+column+format+in+mu4e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;change the date column format in mu4e - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e/HV-Overview.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mu4e 0.9.16 user manual: HV Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=increase+column+size+in+mu4e&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;gws%5Frd=cr&amp;amp;ei=ZjsWV7TDLJW3uQT6qZEY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;increase column size in mu4e - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e/HV-Custom-headers.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mu4e 0.9.16 user manual: HV Custom headers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ftp.fau.de/gentoo/distfiles/mu4e-manual-0.9.9.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mu4e-manual-0.9.9.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=do+mu4e+folders+sync+with+gmail+?&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;gws%5Frd=cr&amp;amp;ei=7DsWV7-NHIyXuASgtJ44#q=do+mu4e+folders+sync+with+gmail+folders&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;do mu4e folders sync with gmail folders - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/3r8dr3/mu4e%5Fsend%5Fmail%5Fwith%5Fcustom%5Fsmtp%5Fand%5Farchive%5Fin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mu4e Send mail with custom SMTP and archive in Gmail &amp;ldquo;Sent&amp;rdquo; folder : emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brool.com/post/using-mu4e/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using mu4e  Brool &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=are+maildir+folders+synced+back+to+gmail+?&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;gws%5Frd=cr&amp;amp;ei=RlwWV5TKKI62uASltLz4Ag&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;are maildir folders synced back to gmail ? - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.offlineimap.org/doc/use%5Fcases.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Some real use cases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://deferred.io/about/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bluishcoder.co.nz/2013/04/30/backing%5Fup%5Fgmail%5Fmessages%5Fwith%5Fofflineimap.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Backing up Gmail messages with offlineimap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.co.in/search?q=notmuch+email+versus+mu4e&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;gws%5Frd=cr&amp;amp;ei=zmcWV8eVEIqdugTzkIpo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;notmuch email versus mu4e - Google Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/3s5fas/which%5Femail%5Fclient%5Fmu4e%5Fmutt%5Fnotmuch%5Fgnus%5Fdo%5Fyou/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Which email client (mu4e, Mutt, notmuch, Gnus) do you use inside Emacs, and why? : emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://irreal.org/blog/?p=2897&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A Followup on Leaving Gmail | Irreal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cscorley.github.io/2014/01/19/sup/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sup?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pbrisbin.com/posts/mutt%5Fgmail%5Fofflineimap/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mutt + Gmail + Offlineimap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pragmaticemacs.com/emacs/migrating-from-offlineimap-to-mbsync-for-mu4e/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Migrating from offlineimap to mbsync for mu4e | Pragmatic Emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;Fastmail allows for a variety of interesting features like aliases, easy email transfer (from a different email provider like Gmail or MSN), responsive technical support, and many more aspects, and much more. They have their own implementation of the IMAP protocol, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastmail.com/help/guides/interfaceupdate-2018.html#what-is-jmap&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;called JMAP&lt;/a&gt;, which is significantly faster.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;While there are many advantages in Gmail and many swear by it&amp;rsquo;s search capabilities - it is worth noting that Fastmail&amp;rsquo;s ad-free interface and search just feels a lot quicker than Gmail, and I can find my way around the settings better than I used to with Gmail.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;You may be surprised to see the ease in browsing a good number of websites on a text based web browser. Besides the added advantage of being within Emacs - a surprising number of websites can be viewed functionally on w3m. It works fine for quick searches on Google (which like anything else, can be done within a few key strokes in Emacs).
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the movie Whiplash</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whiplash%5F%25282014%5Ffilm%2529&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Whiplash: Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiplash is a fascinating movie on many levels regarding a topic that interests me deeply&amp;hellip; How to progressively perform, and strive to become the very best in a chosen field. Personally, I found each step of the movie riveting and would recommend it to anybody who would find the above question even mildly interesting. The movie&amp;rsquo;s climax  was immensely interesting, inspiring and supported by great acting.  At any rate, the movie induced a blog post !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story revolves around the mind and life of a student who wants to be among the greats in his field, and the way he deals with an abrasive, abusive and unorthodox teacher whose intentions are to bring out the best in a student. No movie is perfect - while some points in Whiplash do appear extreme and therefore relatively unrealistic - the overriding message and theme conveyed certainly rings out clearly, in an engaging plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could relate to the following pointers from the movie:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leverage-stress-to-achieve-new-levels-of-insight-and-performance&#34;&gt;Leverage stress to achieve new levels of insight and performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The belief of the teacher, that the best performance or attributes hidden inside a person can come out only via repeated, unexpected and  stressful prodding. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this works as shown in the movie, but I have found unexpected insights at times of extreme stress, that have were taken forward to habits that changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;weathering-criticism&#34;&gt;Weathering criticism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mental conditioning required to weather and beat intense, sharp,
depressing criticism along with verbal and physical abuse from a
mentor or teacher and use the same as a motive force for
self-improvement and eventually superlative performance. Though there
are examples of extreme abrasiveness in leaders like Steve Jobs - such
an approach would not be tolerated by most people today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know other stories of people working under such mentors,
striving to learn and gain their approval and eventually winning
the same. These efforts paid off by resulting in skills, thinking
patterns and a superior mental conditioning. Finding such a mentor
at the formative stage is probably the best thing to happen to
anybody.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An effective strategy to find mentors is to shadow people on Linked in and learn from their profiles and activity. Some of them may be willing to connect and invest time in mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another possibility to find like minded people and mentors would be to join the communities of on-line courses, like Datacamp and Dataquest, who have lively channels in Slack for paid members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-back-up-after-a-fall&#34;&gt;Getting back up after a fall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody breaks. Just as the promising student in Whiplash
breaks. But the champions among us rally, to stage a comeback and
performance that make history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regularly surpassing the level of deliberate knowledge of your own performance, and thus improvement by exactly being able to measure your performance and pinpoint mistakes. This point is portrayed in a very interesting manner in Whiplash, where the teacher expects the student to know exactly what mistake is being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-great-not-good&#34;&gt;Be Great, not Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rejecting the &amp;lsquo;Good&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Good enough&amp;rsquo; feedback from anybody. The goal is to be &lt;em&gt;Great&lt;/em&gt;, not good. The goal should be to strive to set the precedent and not just follow a beaten track. The pinpoint focus should be on progressive improvement to become the best, and that entails never being satisfied and to be ruthless in rooting out flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;achieving-balance-mind-body-surroundings&#34;&gt;Achieving Balance : mind + body + surroundings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great performance is about that perfect balance between the body, mind and environment to leverage the best result possible. I view the scene where the student survives a car crash, just to reach a performance and then not being able to perform, as a good example of overreaching, without strengthening the core, and thus inviting instability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-off-the-beaten-track-and-lose-yourself&#34;&gt;Go off the beaten track and Lose yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the ending of Whiplash that truly drove me to comprehend the points so far. It is twisted, unexpected and led me to truly enjoy the movie and appreciate that: despite the above points being reasonably discernible - the human mind and nature is exceedingly complex. Stability and reasoning are not the only keystones to the foundation of greatness. There has to be a &lt;em&gt;healthy&lt;/em&gt; mix of some form of abnormal obsession thrown in, to make a stellar performance what it is. However, can this be practically repeated on a regular basis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-velocity-and-flow&#34;&gt;Learning velocity and Flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several bodies of research work available today that can be studied to get closer to consciously stimulating a great performance. One such example is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unmistakablecreative.com/podcast/unlocking-the-talent-code-with-dan-coyle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Unlocking the Talent Code With Dan Coyle&lt;/a&gt; on the Unmistakable
Creatives podcast provides an insight in line with the points seen
above, into what constitute outliers and performers. The interesting
concept of &amp;lsquo;Learning velocity&amp;rsquo; is explained by Dan with a lucid
example. It is surmised that progress and maximum learning to become
better occurs &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; the boundary line dividing what we know at the
moment, and the unknown skills that beckon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That point sems to be an amalgamation of several factors, that are typically present when someone is in &amp;lsquo;flow&amp;rsquo;. Perhaps this flow can be described as a heightened sense of what is, and what should be and the energy to strive and achieve what should be.. It certainly does feel logical to think that we become better by pushing that boundary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juggling multiple projects and leveraging org-projectile</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/8f702ce2-8bb7-40a3-b44b-a47222c02909/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/8f702ce2-8bb7-40a3-b44b-a47222c02909/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkitchin/scimax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scimax&lt;/a&gt; has a convenient feature of immediately creating projects (&lt;code&gt;M-x nb-new&lt;/code&gt;). The location of the project directory is defined by the setting &lt;code&gt;(setq nb-notebook-directory &amp;quot;~/my_projects/&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;, which has to be set in your Emacs config. Once the name of the project is chosen, a Readme.org buffer is immediately opened and one can start right away. It is an awesome, friction-free method to get started with a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These projects are automatically initialised as git repositories, to which it is trivial to add a new remote using Magit. Therefore individual folders and git repos are automatically created for each project in the specified project directory. This enables the convenient possibility of keeping the data, folder structures, tasks, notes and scripts of each project separate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different projects can be switched to using &lt;code&gt;M-x nb-open&lt;/code&gt; and typing in a few words that denote the title of the project. Choosing a project automatically provides the option to open the Readme.org files created earlier. Therefore it would be convenient to include relevant links to different locations / scripts and etc in the Readme file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the above technique resulted in me creating a huge number of projects over a period of time. Especially while working on multiple computers, it is worth inculcating the discipline of adding a remote on github/bitbucket and regularly pushing to the remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage of using a separate repo for each project is the alignment with the space constraints imposed by the free tier repos on bitbucket or github. However, it is also useful to have the entire project folder as a git repo. This can be resolved by adding each project as a sub-module. In this way, all the projects are available with a single clone of the project foder, and then specific sub-modules or projects can be initialized as required. Having separate repos for each project also enables more streamlined collaboration or publishing of a particular project, rather than the entire project folder and allowing separate gitignore lists for each project.Using a single file for all the projects will also enable adding notes pertaining to the content of each project, which can be searched before intialising the entire project repo. Scripts for initializing and commit can also be included in this file for convenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the above is done, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/IvanMalison/org-projectile/blob/master/org-projectile.el&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;org-projectile&lt;/a&gt; package can be leveraged to plan the tasks and manage the notes for each project. It is possible to have all the tasks for a project within a separate file within each project, or specify a single file as the task management for all the projects. This file is then appended to the org-agenda files for tasks to show up in the agenda. As mentioned in the Readme of the org-projectile package the settings would look like the following (for a single file pertaining to all the projects):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; Setting up org-projectile&lt;/span&gt;
(require &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;org-projectile&lt;/span&gt;)
(setq org-projectile-projects-file
      &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/my_org/project-tasks.org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
(push (org-projectile-project-todo-entry) org-capture-templates)
(setq org-agenda-files (append org-agenda-files (org-projectile-todo-files)))
(global-set-key (kbd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;C-c n p&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;org-projectile-project-todo-completing-read&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above snippet adds a TODO capture template activated by the letter &amp;lsquo;p&amp;rsquo;, and also adds the &lt;code&gt;project-tasks&lt;/code&gt; file to the agenda files. Inside a project, it is then possible to capture using &lt;code&gt;C-cc p&lt;/code&gt; and add a task which will create a top level heading linked to the project, and the task or note as a sub-heading.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/screenshot-org-projectile.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;org-projectile task capture&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter notebooks to Org source &#43; Tower of Babel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post provides a simple example demonstrating how a shell script can be called with appropriate variables from any Org file in Emacs. The script essentially converts a Jupyter notebook to Org source, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://orgmode.org/worg/org-contrib/babel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Babel&lt;/a&gt; is leveraged to call the script with appropriate variables from any Org file. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=11296843&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;reddit thread&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lepisma.github.io/2016/11/02/org-babel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; elucidate the advantages of using Babel and Org mode over Jupyter notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly editing code in a Jupyter notebook in a browser is not an attractive long term option and is inconvenient even in the short term. My preference is to have it all in Emacs, leveraging a versatile Org file where it is easy to encapsulate code in notebooks or projects within Org-headings. Thus, projects are integrated with the in-built task management and calendar of Org mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it may be a frequent necessity to access an external Jupyter notebook for which there is no Org source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One solution is to start up a Jupyter server locally, open the file and then File &amp;gt;&amp;gt; save as a markdown file, which can be converted to an Org file using pandoc. Remarkably, the output code seems similar to the code blocks used in the R-markdown notebooks, rather than pure markdown markup. Therefore this markdown export should work fine in RStudio as well. However, unless the Jupyter server is always running on your machine, this is a relatively slow, multi-step process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://emacs.stackexchange.com/questions/5465/how-to-migrate-markdown-files-to-emacs-org-mode-format&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This SO discussion&lt;/a&gt; provided my answer, which is a 2 step script via the versatile &lt;a href=&#34;https://pandoc.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;. A workable solution, as a test conversion revealed. The headings and subheadings and code are converted into Org markup along with Org source blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sh&#34; data-lang=&#34;sh&#34;&gt;jupyter nbconvert notebook.ipynb --to markdown
pandoc notebook.md -o notebook.org&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next consideration was to have the above script or recipe handy for converting any Jupyter notebook to an Org file quickly.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; For the script to be referenced and called from any other location,  the source block needs to be defined with a name and the necessary arguments, and also added into the org-babel library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example the path to the Jupyter notebook, markdown file and resulting org file are specified as variables or arguments. Note that the absolute path to any file is required. Save the following in an Org file, named appropriately, like my-recipes.org&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;#+&lt;/span&gt;NAME: jupyter-to-org-current
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;#+&lt;/span&gt;HEADER:  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:var&lt;/span&gt; path_ipynb=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/Users/xxx/Jupyter_notebook&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;#+&lt;/span&gt;HEADER: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:var&lt;/span&gt; path_md = &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Jupyter_notebook-markdown&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;#+&lt;/span&gt;HEADER: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:var&lt;/span&gt; path_org = &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Jupyter-notebook-org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;#+&lt;/span&gt;BEGIN_SRC sh &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:results&lt;/span&gt; verbatim
cwd=$(pwd)
jupyter nbconvert --to markdown $path_ipynb.ipynb --output $cwd/$path_md.md
pandoc $cwd/$path_md.md -o $cwd/$path_org.org
cp $path_ipynb.ipynb $cwd
ls&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;path_ipynb&lt;/code&gt; variable can be changed as required to point to the Jupyter notebook.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All such blocks above can be stored in Org files and added to the Library of Babel (LOB) by including the following in the Emacs init configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;(org-babel-lob-ingest &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/Users/shreyas/my_projects/my-recipes.org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The named shell script source block can now be called from any Org file, with specified arguments and have the notebook. The script is called using the &lt;code&gt;#+CALL&lt;/code&gt; function and using the name and arguments of the source block above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;#+&lt;/span&gt;CALL: jupyter-to-org-current(path_md=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Jup-to-markdown&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; path_org=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Markdown-to-org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the snippet above will convert a Jupyter notebook to a markdown file named &lt;code&gt;Jup-to-markdown&lt;/code&gt; and then an Org file called &lt;code&gt;Markdown-to-org&lt;/code&gt;. If an argument is not specified, the default value of the paths specified in the original source block will be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the &lt;code&gt;#+CALL&lt;/code&gt; function used above is also too lengthy to remember and reproduce without headaches. This is also bound to happen as the number of such named code snippets increase. One solution (though not ideal) is to store the &lt;code&gt;#+CALL&lt;/code&gt; as a snippet using &lt;code&gt;M-x&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code&gt;yas-new-snippet&lt;/code&gt;, and load it when needed using the excellent &lt;code&gt;ivy-yasnippet&lt;/code&gt; package (see MELPA), with minimal exertions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-possibilities&#34;&gt;Further possibilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to improve the options available for modifications on the fly. Python may be an &amp;lsquo;easier&amp;rsquo; option to write up for such activities rather than a shell script. For example, a script with the working directory being an additional /optional argument could be considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another desirable factor in the resulting Org file would be iPython blocks in place of python. As a temporary solution, the python blocks could be converted to ipython blocks via a search and replace throughout the document. A lisp macro / source block could run after the above source block to facilitate the search and replace.&amp;nbsp;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkitchin/scimax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scimax&lt;/a&gt; - it is possible to quickly start a new project using &lt;code&gt;M-x nb-new&lt;/code&gt;, which creates a sub-folder in the specified projects folder and creates and opens a readme.org file for the project.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;The option &lt;code&gt;C-u-cl&lt;/code&gt; is a messy way to quickly get the full file name path, the resulting path will need to be modified slightly.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;It is worth noting that a bunch of additional HTML blocks and hyperlinks are inserted via the above export procedure. It should be possible to add some hooks to clean up the org file after the export from pandoc.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs notes: Select paragraph and browse-kill-ring for effective content capture</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2d1b3227-28de-4b30-93c8-ad5cbe276e44/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2d1b3227-28de-4b30-93c8-ad5cbe276e44/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like to have any reading material and my notes side by side&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This is easily done with Emacs by splitting the buffer vertically (&lt;code&gt;C-x 3&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: Once a link has been opened via w3m, I hit org-capture (&lt;code&gt;C-c&lt;/code&gt;) with a preset template that grabs the URL to the article along with the created date in the properties, with the cursor in position ready to take notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;(setq org-capture-templates
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;((&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;l&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Link + notes&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; entry (file+headline &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/my_org/link_database.org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;.UL Unfiled Links&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;** %? %a &amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snippet above is activated by the command &amp;lsquo;l&amp;rsquo; and is listed with the title Link + notes in the agenda. It captures the link of the file being viewed as the heading and allows further notes to be inserted below. This is stored into the file &lt;code&gt;link_database&lt;/code&gt; and under the specified heading &lt;code&gt;.UL Unfiled Links&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to capture a highlighted chunk of text to be added under the heading mentioned above. That would look something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;(setq org-capture-templates
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;((&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;e&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Snippet + Notes&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; entry &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;;; &amp;#39;w&amp;#39; for &amp;#39;org-protocol&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
     (file+headline &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;~/my_org/link_database.org&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;.UL Unfiled Links&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)
     &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;*** %a, %T\n %:initial&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;)))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have the capture buffer and the viewing content side by side, by calling &lt;code&gt;C-c l&lt;/code&gt;. I can browse through the article use the mark-paragraph function (conveniently set to &lt;code&gt;M-h&lt;/code&gt;) can be used to select and copy (&lt;code&gt;M-w&lt;/code&gt;) entire paragraphs or alternately use &lt;code&gt;C-spc&lt;/code&gt; to select lines of interest from the article them to the kill ring. The figure below depicts how it looks for me:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/capture-content-emacs.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Emacs content capture and buffer split&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to continue highlighting interesting lines / paragraphs and copy them, which adds them to the kill-ring. Once the article is done with, I switch over to the capture buffer and hit &lt;code&gt;M-x&lt;/code&gt; browse-kill-ring, which brings up a pop-up buffer with all the items in the kill-ring&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Once called, I can hit n to move to the next item, and hit &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo; to insert the current item at the cursor location. It is also possible to append / prepend/ edit the item before yanking. All the available shortcuts can be found using &amp;lsquo;?&amp;rsquo;, while in the browse-kill-ring buffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above methodology curiously enables me to ensure capturing atleast some details of interest from an article / source, and also serve as a quick revision of the read content before filing it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue with the above workflow is that while reading multiple articles, there is a chance of mixing up the content being captured from different articles. This could be solved by using &amp;lsquo;x&amp;rsquo; in order to pop items out of the kill ring in the selection process above. However, it seems excessive to clear the entire kill ring for each article read. On the other hand, it could promote a focused workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional possibilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To view pdf files side by side and capture notes is via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rudolfochrist/interleave&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interleave package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The org-web-clipper concept outlined &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bobnewell.net/publish/35years/webclipper.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is also very convenient to rapidly capture entire webpages being browsed in w3m.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Howard Abrams has &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.howardism.org/Technical/Emacs/capturing-intro.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;some great tips&lt;/a&gt; on customising the org-capture mechanism,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://doc.norang.ca/org-mode.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bernt Hansen&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;Sometimes, this procedure has to be set specifically. Some good discussions on SO : &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2081577/setting-emacs-split-to-horizontal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/7997590/how-to-change-the-default-split-screen-direction&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link2&lt;/a&gt;. However, at times horizontal splitting is useful. Therefore, I would rather not set a 0 width-threshold enabling only vertical splitting. &lt;code&gt;lisp (setq split-width-threshold 75) (setq split-height-threshold nil)&lt;/code&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C-x&lt;/code&gt; essentially means Control + x. &lt;code&gt;M-x&lt;/code&gt; or Meta-x is Alt + x
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-3&#34;&gt;The browse-kill-ring package can be installed via MELPA. (&lt;code&gt;M-x&lt;/code&gt; install package)
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iosevka - an awesome font for Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before my foray into Emacs, I purchased applications like &lt;a href=&#34;https://ia.net/writer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IAWriter&lt;/a&gt;
(classic)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://brettterpstra.com/2017/08/01/long-form-writing-with-marked-2-plus-2-dot-5-11-teaser/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marked2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.texts.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Texts&lt;/a&gt; (cross platform Mac/Windows), and have
also tried almost all the recommended apps for longer form writing. I
am a fan of zen writing apps. In particular the font and environment
provided by IAWriter are conducive to focused writing. There also
exist apps like Hemingway that also help check the quality of your
writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zen writing apps are called so because they have a unique combination
of fonts, background color, including line spacing and overall
text-width - all of which enable a streamlined and focused flow of
words onto the screen. Any customisation required towards this end is
possible in Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Texts app has some nifty features (besides being cross platform),
but the font and appearance is not as beautiful as IAWriter. Both
IAWriter (classic) and Texts have minimal settings for further
customisation. See the comparison below:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/emacs-texts.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Emacs (writeroom-mode + Iosevka font) || Texts (Sepia theme)&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;https://shrysr.github.io/img/emacs-iawriter.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Emacs (writeroom-mode, Iosevka font) || IAWriter(Classic)&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While everybody&amp;rsquo;s style and approach vary, there are many authors who
swear by archaic text editors and tools that enable distraction free
writing. One example is &lt;a href=&#34;http://tonyballantyne.com/how-to-write/writing-tools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tony Ballantyne&amp;rsquo;s post on writing tools&lt;/a&gt;,
and several more examples are available in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://irreal.org/blog/?p=4651&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next best thing to a clear retina display on a MacBook Pro, is a
beautiful font face to take you through the day, enhancing the viewing
pleasure and thus the motivation to work longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Emacs, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/joostkremers/writeroom-mode&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;writeroom-mode&lt;/a&gt; and Emacs can be customised to
mimic IAWriter. In this regard, the font &lt;a href=&#34;https://be5invis.github.io/Iosevka/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Iosevka&lt;/a&gt;, is a great font to
try. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/emacs/comments/5twcka/which%5Ffont%5Fdo%5Fyou%5Fuse/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;old Emacs reddit&lt;/a&gt; has many more suggestions. One post
described Iosevka as &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;it&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like much, but after a few hours
it will be difficult to&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;use any other font.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; This is exactly what
happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of tweaking to be done with &lt;code&gt;writeroom-mode&lt;/code&gt;,
but this is certainly a workable result. My nascent configuration for
writeroom-mode in emacs is as follows (munged off the internet!). It&amp;rsquo;s
remarkable how much was achieved with a few lines of code!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lisp&#34; data-lang=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;(with-eval-after-load &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;writeroom-mode&lt;/span&gt;
  (define-key writeroom-mode-map (kbd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;C-s-,&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;#&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;writeroom-decrease-width)
  (define-key writeroom-mode-map (kbd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;C-s-.&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;#&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;writeroom-increase-width)
  (define-key writeroom-mode-map (kbd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;C-s-=&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;#&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;writeroom-adjust-width))

(advice-add &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;text-scale-adjust&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;:after&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;#&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;visual-fill-column-adjust)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;The latest version of IAWriter has a truck load of features and advantages over over the Classic version. I did consider purchasing it, but Emacs won the day. Nevertheless, as a plain vanilla writing app - IAWriter offers much right out of the box.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
