<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 08:43:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash scripting to compare chat logs of an IRC channel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/bash-scripting-mini-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 08:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/bash-scripting-mini-project/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Summary Preliminary notes: Plan Simple case Including variables for url prefix, start id and end id Figuring out a larger range  Implementing a simple conditional statement Implementing the for loop for a range &amp;gt; 500 Adding some functions and other minor streamlining  Enabling the script to be called with parameters Comparing logs for range 9998683 to 1000000 Concluding remarks References</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iosevka - an awesome font for Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</guid>
      <description>Before my foray into Emacs, I purchased applications like IAWriter (classic)1, Marked2, Texts (cross platform Mac/Windows), and have also tried almost all the recommended apps for longer form writing. I am a fan of zen writing apps. In particular the font and environment provided by IAWriter are conducive to focused writing. There also exist apps like Hemingway that also help check the quality of your writing.
Zen writing apps are called so because they have a unique combination of fonts, background color, including line spacing and overall text-width - all of which enable a streamlined and focused flow of words onto the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux notes</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/linux-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:53:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/linux-notes/</guid>
      <description>Installing the Iosevka font On Debian distros There appear to be no packages for iosevka for debian. The prescribed method is to add the fonts to the fonts folder. The github issues point towards a PPA which can be added. However, this did not work for me, and I had to resort to manual means.
Downloading the specified font version from github into a temp folder
cd ~/temp wget &amp;#34;https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An SSD can breathe life into old computers</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/01252410-853f-4570-858f-f3d609f5def5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/01252410-853f-4570-858f-f3d609f5def5/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a well known trick that installing a SSD in place of the conventional Hard disk can breathe new life into very old machines. My mid 2010 Macbook Pro is one such example, being over 8 years old.
In particular, within Emacs - mu4e responds much more quickly and there is significantly less lag in searching / accessing emails and HTML rendering.
The other advantage of using a Mac over Linux is that installation and setup instructions are more often available out the box for the Mac OS (though this is changing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributions to the CFD-Online Wiki</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-on-line-wiki/cfd-online-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-on-line-wiki/cfd-online-wiki/</guid>
      <description>View : CFD-Online Wiki page.
Motivation During my initial foray into open source CFD and especially getting started with Linux - there was a lot of information that I had to collate from different sources in order to figure out each step. In addition, there were perspectives on performance that could be gained only through experience. Therefore, I plugged back the knowledge gained to the CFD-Online wiki with the idea that it would help any newbie get started a little quicker.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>