<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/categories/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/categories/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ESS for Datascience</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</guid>
      <description>RStudio is a formidable IDE to work with and offers an environment to seamlessly work with multiple languages beyond R. It is especially convenient for tasks involving frequent visualisation of data frames and plots, and for use with Shiny app development.
However, the text (i.e code) editing capabalities are still significantly lacking compared to the likes of Emacs and Vim. Besides this, it does not offer a seamless interface integrating task, time management and multi-language programming environments to the extent available within Org-mode via Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Programming - Emacs, Howard Abrams and Library of Babel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/6953c104-a8b3-4779-aad3-c33032beb111/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/6953c104-a8b3-4779-aad3-c33032beb111/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an admirer of Howard Abrams, especially because his posts and videos show the awesome power of doing things in Emacs, and the importance of writing clean and logical code. Watching his videos and reading his posts make me feel like I was born yesterday and I am just getting started. But more importantly, they also fire up my imagination regarding the possibilities out there and the potential to create glorious workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Emacs &#43; Scimax configuration</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/sr-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 15:49:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/sr-config/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is my literate, Org-mode based configuration for Emacs, which are essentially customisations built on top of the starter-kit Scimax. View a nicely rendered version with easy navigation on my website, or if you prefer: on github.
 Scimax - Awesome editing for scientists and engineers. Scimax is an Emacs starterkit for scientists and engineers. It provides a comprehensive configuration of Emacs for scientific programming and publishing.
John Kitchin</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>