<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching the awesome-lists on github</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/03133c10-709e-4d06-9f3d-c00ffeae64a7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/03133c10-709e-4d06-9f3d-c00ffeae64a7/</guid>
      <description>I came upon the glorious awesome lists today on Github. These repositories can be viewed with a simple search on github. They contain all kinds of lists on all kinds of topics, and are curated.
Beware! the number of lists and the number of items being covered are quite extensive. There are a lot of common grounds and topics between these lists.
I wanted to search for a keyword through all these repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iosevka - one font closer to zen writing</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</guid>
      <description>I have recently returned to my MacBook Pro as the primary driver for daily work. While I do enjoy using Antergos / Arch Linux - at this time the primary reason is that my macbook has an SSD, which makes things significantly faster in all respects.1 , 2 , 3
Before my foray into Emacs, I purchased applications like IAWriter (classic), Marked2, Texts (cross platform Mac/Windows) and also tried several other free apps for longer form writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the movie Whiplash</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</guid>
      <description>Whiplash: Wikipedia
Whiplash is a fascinating movie on many levels regarding a topic that interests me deeply&amp;#x2026; How to progressively perform, and strive to become the very best in a chosen field. Personally, I found each step of the movie riveting and would recommend it to anybody who would find the above question even mildly interesting. The movie&amp;rsquo;s climax was immensely interesting, inspiring and supported by great acting. At any rate, the movie induced a blog post&amp;#x2026;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>