<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 08:02:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Org-mode configuration for Emacs is liberating</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/d16caa34-c2e2-439b-894f-d95be5708160/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 08:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/d16caa34-c2e2-439b-894f-d95be5708160/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Check out the Docs section for my Emacs config in Org-mode
 The literate programming paradigm, as conceived by Donald Knuth, represents a move away from writing programs in the manner and order imposed by the computer, and instead enables programmers to develop programs in the order demanded by the logic and flow of their thoughts. Literate programs are written as an uninterrupted exposition of logic in an ordinary human language, much like the text of an essay, in which macros are included to hide abstractions and traditional source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental improvements can lead to significant gains</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/32266f09-c9b9-48ff-9c48-e2348eeda33d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/32266f09-c9b9-48ff-9c48-e2348eeda33d/</guid>
      <description>While reading the book Atomic Habits by James Clear, I was reflecting that my choice of embracing Emacs and progressively gaining mastery over it was intimately connected with the philosophy preached in the book.
My efforts initially started out with a craving for a system to quantify and manage my tasks, habits, notes, blog writing, job applications and projects in a custom environment, and to be able to build toolkits of code to perform repetitive tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nteract : An interactive computing environment</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</guid>
      <description>A slide deck from Netflix, mentions using Nteract as their programming notebook, and prompted a mini exploration.
This blog post by Safia Abdalla, (a maintainer/ developer of Nteract) introduces Nteract as an open source, desktop-based, interactive computing application that was designed to overcome a bunch of limitations in Jupyter Notebook&amp;rsquo;s design philosophy. One key difference (among many others) is the ability to execute code in a variety of languages within a single notebook, and it also appears that that the electron based desktop app should make it easier for beginners to start coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leverage recorded macros to learn elisp and hack together workflows in Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/7b7b94ca-2d77-4814-8cae-c9e95d3f8bc4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:16:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/7b7b94ca-2d77-4814-8cae-c9e95d3f8bc4/</guid>
      <description>The primary power of Emacs is that you can create customised workflows to suit your needs. However, lisp is probably not a language that many learn as a typical requirement in the academic systems, perhaps even for a software engineer.
How would one then start customisting Emacs? One way would be to hunt for snippets from forums like reddit and stack overflow, and customise them.
Another easy way to learn a programming language, especially one that is intrinsic to a software is to record macros and edit these macros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical notes : Research paper on learning/teaching data science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</guid>
      <description>Title: Navigating Diverse Data Science Learning: Critical Reflections Towards Future Practice
Author: Yehia Elkhatib
Download link
This are my notes on the above paper, which mainly deals with detailing the methods explored and implemented to impart a high quality of education in data science. The paper also provides an interesting breakup of the different roles in data science workflows.
 The importance of being able to work in a team is highlighted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why bother with Emacs and workflows?</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/11ef85e6-9efc-4af4-b5f3-7648f9ee9308/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 12:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/11ef85e6-9efc-4af4-b5f3-7648f9ee9308/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written several posts on different ways and tools available to aid productivity, and probably a lot about Emacs. My background is in computational physics, and not in programming, and yet Emacs has been an indispensable driver of my daily workflow for the past 3 years.
The fact is that knowing Emacs (or Vim), or having a custom configuration is not a wildly marketable skill, nor is it mandatory to achieve spectacular results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly accessing cheatsheets to learn data science with Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</guid>
      <description>Matt Dancho&amp;rsquo;s course DSB-101-R is an awesome course to step into ROI driven business analytics fueled by Data Science. In this course, among many other things - he teaches methods to understand and use cheatsheets to gain rapid level-ups, especially to find information connecting various packages and functions and workflows. I have been hooked to this approach and needed a way to quickly refer to the different cheatsheets as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to RSS</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:51:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</guid>
      <description>Why use RSS? Off late, I had been relying more on email based content consumption. The phenomenally fast search and filtering capabilities that can be leveraged with mu4e make this easy.
Even with all these filters, it is quite difficult to keep on top of news and information from different sources. It is actually inconvenient to mix important emails and correspondence with newsletters and the like, which arrive by the dozen(s) everyday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archaic text based email clients rock!</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e4e7ebb1-4c0c-41d6-b7e4-1c1c09e48c80/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 19:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e4e7ebb1-4c0c-41d6-b7e4-1c1c09e48c80/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  TLDR - for the busy folks  Goals: Summary:  Multiple email accounts. Lack of a unified interface. Creating sync channels via mbsync Text based email client! Speed + simplicity Why mu4e rocks [for me] - the perks Quirks Multiple levels of filters are still necessary. Takeaways Links and References   
This dev.to blog post inspired me to complete this languishing draft of my current email setup, and the benefits I&amp;rsquo;ve gained from using a text based email client in Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the movie Whiplash</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</guid>
      <description>Whiplash: Wikipedia
Whiplash is a fascinating movie on many levels regarding a topic that interests me deeply&amp;hellip; How to progressively perform, and strive to become the very best in a chosen field. Personally, I found each step of the movie riveting and would recommend it to anybody who would find the above question even mildly interesting. The movie&amp;rsquo;s climax was immensely interesting, inspiring and supported by great acting. At any rate, the movie induced a blog post !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juggling multiple projects and leveraging org-projectile</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/8f702ce2-8bb7-40a3-b44b-a47222c02909/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/8f702ce2-8bb7-40a3-b44b-a47222c02909/</guid>
      <description>Scimax has a convenient feature of immediately creating projects (M-x nb-new). The location of the project directory is defined by the setting (setq nb-notebook-directory &amp;quot;~/my_projects/&amp;quot;), which has to be set in your Emacs config. Once the name of the project is chosen, a Readme.org buffer is immediately opened and one can start right away. It is an awesome, friction-free method to get started with a project.
These projects are automatically initialised as git repositories, to which it is trivial to add a new remote using Magit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter notebooks to Org source &#43; Tower of Babel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a simple example demonstrating how a shell script can be called with appropriate variables from any Org file in Emacs. The script essentially converts a Jupyter notebook to Org source, and Babel is leveraged to call the script with appropriate variables from any Org file. This reddit thread and blog post elucidate the advantages of using Babel and Org mode over Jupyter notebooks.
Directly editing code in a Jupyter notebook in a browser is not an attractive long term option and is inconvenient even in the short term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs notes: Select paragraph and browse-kill-ring for effective content capture</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2d1b3227-28de-4b30-93c8-ad5cbe276e44/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2d1b3227-28de-4b30-93c8-ad5cbe276e44/</guid>
      <description>I like to have any reading material and my notes side by side1. This is easily done with Emacs by splitting the buffer vertically (C-x 3)2
For example: Once a link has been opened via w3m, I hit org-capture (C-c) with a preset template that grabs the URL to the article along with the created date in the properties, with the cursor in position ready to take notes.
(setq org-capture-templates &amp;#39;((&amp;#34;l&amp;#34; &amp;#34;Link + notes&amp;#34; entry (file+headline &amp;#34;~/my_org/link_database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iosevka - an awesome font for Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</guid>
      <description>Before my foray into Emacs, I purchased applications like IAWriter (classic)1, Marked2, Texts (cross platform Mac/Windows), and have also tried almost all the recommended apps for longer form writing. I am a fan of zen writing apps. In particular the font and environment provided by IAWriter are conducive to focused writing. There also exist apps like Hemingway that also help check the quality of your writing.
Zen writing apps are called so because they have a unique combination of fonts, background color, including line spacing and overall text-width - all of which enable a streamlined and focused flow of words onto the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching the awesome-lists on Github</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/03133c10-709e-4d06-9f3d-c00ffeae64a7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:38:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/03133c10-709e-4d06-9f3d-c00ffeae64a7/</guid>
      <description>Discovered the glorious awesome lists today on Github. They are available through a simple search on github, and contain curated lists of resources of all kinds on a multitude of topics.
As one might expect, there is a lot of common ground between these lists, including topics and links.
How could one search for a keyword through all these repositories? I have always wanted search for particular keywords or code snippets in my Emacs configuration files, or in other files in a particular location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Programming - Emacs, Howard Abrams and Library of Babel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/6953c104-a8b3-4779-aad3-c33032beb111/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/6953c104-a8b3-4779-aad3-c33032beb111/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an admirer of Howard Abrams, especially because his posts and videos show the awesome power of doing things in Emacs, and the importance of writing clean and logical code. Watching his videos and reading his posts make me feel like I was born yesterday and I am just getting started. But more importantly, they also fire up my imagination regarding the possibilities out there and the potential to create glorious workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An SSD can breathe life into old computers</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/01252410-853f-4570-858f-f3d609f5def5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/01252410-853f-4570-858f-f3d609f5def5/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a well known trick that installing a SSD in place of the conventional Hard disk can breathe new life into very old machines. My mid 2010 Macbook Pro is one such example, being over 8 years old.
In particular, within Emacs - mu4e responds much more quickly and there is significantly less lag in searching / accessing emails and HTML rendering.
The other advantage of using a Mac over Linux is that installation and setup instructions are more often available out the box for the Mac OS (though this is changing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching from Evernote to DEVONtechnologies products</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/ec354a8e-a276-4c89-8560-ce82b1693744/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/ec354a8e-a276-4c89-8560-ce82b1693744/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used Evernote since 2014, with over 3k notes of all kinds stored in it. Though I did try to capture everything of interest - the procedure was never fast or streamlined enough for me. The Evernote app runs ridiculously slower on older phones. In particular, being used to the speed of Emacs and Org mode - I was mostly displeased with the Evernote Mac / Windows apps as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting productive - an exploration into holistic task management</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To integrate tasks, reminders, notes, coding workflow into a single framework is no easy challenge. Org mode and Emacs help you do just that.
After trying out several tools, IMHO : Todoist offers the best bang for your buck, especially with it&amp;rsquo;s natural language parsing ability, smooth and reliable sync as well as its multi-platform availability. Many describe Omnifocus to be the king of task management tools, with dedicated apps for different purposes and probably well integrated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>