<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Science on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Science on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 23:23:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes on research-compendium</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/research-compendium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 23:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/research-compendium/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes while studying the research-compendium concept, which is essentially a bunch of guidelines to produce research that is &amp;lsquo;easily&amp;rsquo; reproducible.
The notes are mostly based on marwick-2018-packag-r , which is one canonical reading on the concept. Other references are mentioned throughout the text, and also collected separately. These notes were prepared a few weeks ago during a foray into Docker. They are neither complete not comprehensive - but will serve as a good refresher of the principle concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ESS for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</guid>
      <description>RStudio is a formidable IDE to work with and offers an environment to seamlessly work with multiple languages beyond R. It is especially convenient for tasks involving frequent visualisation of data frames and plots, and for use with Shiny app development.
However, the text (i.e code) editing capabalities are still significantly lacking compared to the likes of Emacs and Vim. Besides this, it does not offer a seamless interface integrating task, time management and multi-language programming environments to the extent available within Org-mode via Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nteract : An interactive computing environment</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</guid>
      <description>A slide deck from Netflix, mentions using Nteract as their programming notebook, and prompted a mini exploration.
This blog post by Safia Abdalla, (a maintainer/ developer of Nteract) introduces Nteract as an open source, desktop-based, interactive computing application that was designed to overcome a bunch of limitations in Jupyter Notebook&amp;rsquo;s design philosophy. One key difference (among many others) is the ability to execute code in a variety of languages within a single notebook, and it also appears that that the electron based desktop app should make it easier for beginners to start coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly accessing cheatsheets to learn data science with Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</guid>
      <description>Matt Dancho&amp;rsquo;s course DSB-101-R is an awesome course to step into ROI driven business analytics fueled by Data Science. In this course, among many other things - he teaches methods to understand and use cheatsheets to gain rapid level-ups, especially to find information connecting various packages and functions and workflows. I have been hooked to this approach and needed a way to quickly refer to the different cheatsheets as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federal R&amp;D Spending on climate change</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/tt-fed-rnd-spending/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/tt-fed-rnd-spending/</guid>
      <description>Summary This is a short exploration into the tidy tuesday dataset focused on the Federal R&amp;amp;D budget towards global climate change. The data has been extracted from a TidyTuesday dataset, which in return is moderately cleaned dataset from publicly available data. The analysis will show that NASA&amp;rsquo;s budget dwarfs the money going into other departments, and that the median spend towards climate change has been increasing since the year 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Docker</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/docker-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 14:33:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/docker-notes/</guid>
      <description>Docker is a fascinating concept that could be potentially useful in many ways, especially in Data science, and making reproducible workflows / environments. There are several articles which have great introductions and examples of using docker in data science
This is an evolving summary of my exploration with Docker. It should prove to be a handy refresher of commands and concepts.
TODO What is Docker A brief summary of what Docker is all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R notes and snippets</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 11:21:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Lubridate - introductory technical paper This paper (Grolemund and Wickham) offers a good introduction and comparison between using lubridate and not using it, as well as several examples of using the library. It also offers some case studies which can serve as useful drill exercises.
Importing multiple excel sheets from multiple excel files This is one approach to importing multiple sheets from multiple excel files into a list of tibbles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB and NoSQL Databases</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/nosql-mongodb-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 12:12:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/nosql-mongodb-notes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction These are my notes on NoSQL databases and the prime differences between them and SQL databases. The notes are mostly based off the Udemy course Introduction to MongoDB, and therefore primarily focused on using MongoDB at the moment.
Methodology and Tools Installing Mongodb The instructions are available in the mongoDB manual. This is for the Community edition, and on a Mac as welll as Linux machine (Antergos)
Mac If never installed before, tap the resource first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Certificates</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/course-certificate-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/course-certificate-list/</guid>
      <description> EdX  EdX HarvardX PH125.1x Data Science Basics: R.  DataCamp  Intro to SQL
 Data Science R basics included in EdX HarvardX PH125.1x
 Introduction to Tidyverse
 Introduction to R for Finance
  DataQuest  Data Analyst Path in R
 Git &amp;amp; Version control
 SQL Fundamentals
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>