<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CFD Post Processing automation</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-post-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-post-automation/</guid>
      <description>It is possible (and prevalent) to create templates to post process CFD Simulation results in ANSYS CFD Post using session (.cse) files. Using Shell scripts, it would then be simple to apply these session files on multiple result files and extract the output dictated by the session file.
This python script that enables the user to set the location of: - the session file (.cse) - the CFD result files (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributions to the CFD-Online Wiki</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-online-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-online-wiki/</guid>
      <description>View : CFD-Online Wiki page.
Motivation During my initial foray into open source CFD and especially getting started with Linux - there was a lot of information that I had to collate from different sources in order to figure out each step. In addition, there were perspectives on performance that could be gained only through experience. Therefore, I plugged back the knowledge gained to the CFD-Online wiki with the idea that it would help any newbie get started a little quicker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of an Electro-mechanical prosthetic finger, and a PID controller for the wrist.</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/kinematic-design-finger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/kinematic-design-finger/</guid>
      <description>This project utilized MATLAB, Solidworks to research and design a human finger and calculate the range of it&amp;rsquo;s motion. SIMULINK is also utilised to design a PID controller for the wrist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation job scheduler</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-simulation-scheduler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/cfd-simulation-scheduler/</guid>
      <description>Scheduler Psuedo-Algorithm   Introduction Code On Github
This is a Python script for a portable, scalable job scheduler with multiple priorities - for ANSYS CFX simulations. The script was designed to be called every minute by an external scheduler program.
 In the practical case, the free version of the software System Scheduler was used to deploy the script successfully, for over 3 years, managing 2 computing clusters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Trends of Emission Reduction Technology in Vehicular Diesel Engines.</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/emission-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/emission-technology/</guid>
      <description>This project undertakes a technology study and survey covering the methods to controlling harmful emission from Diesel engines in particular and the efficacy different technologies. It explores current emission norms and the contradicting formation conditions of NOx and CO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-line Certificate Course:   EdX HarvardX PH125.1x: Data Science: R Basics</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/course-edx-harvard-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/course-edx-harvard-r/</guid>
      <description> Verified Certificate of Achievement  The course covered an introduction to using R to extract, manipulate and thus analyse data. It basically lays the foundations to using R in data science.
 Course Notes and code
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-line Courses:   Code School</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/project/course-code-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/project/course-code-school/</guid>
      <description> Code School Report Card  Completed several courses covering python, git, SQL,regular expressions.
 Most of these courses were completed during the occasional Free Weekend opportunities from Code School, where the paid courses are available to be completed at no cost, for an entire weekend.&amp;rdquo;
  Course Notes and code  Fly with Python  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>