<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DataScience on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/categories/datascience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DataScience on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/categories/datascience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nteract : An interactive computing environment</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</guid>
      <description>A slide deck from Netflix, mentions using Nteract as their programming notebook, and prompted a mini exploration.
This blog post by Safia Abdalla, (a maintainer/ developer of Nteract) introduces Nteract as an open source, desktop-based, interactive computing application that was designed to overcome a bunch of limitations in Jupyter Notebook&amp;rsquo;s design philosophy. One key difference (among many others) is the ability to execute code in a variety of languages within a single notebook, and it also appears that that the electron based desktop app should make it easier for beginners to start coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical notes : Research paper on learning/teaching data science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</guid>
      <description>Title: Navigating Diverse Data Science Learning: Critical Reflections Towards Future Practice
Author: Yehia Elkhatib
Download link
This are my notes on the above paper, which mainly deals with detailing the methods explored and implemented to impart a high quality of education in data science. The paper also provides an interesting breakup of the different roles in data science workflows.
 The importance of being able to work in a team is highlighted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly accessing cheatsheets to learn data science with Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 10:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/e86e171e-cc0d-4957-b587-ed2bbf36a8cf/</guid>
      <description>Matt Dancho&amp;rsquo;s course DSB-101-R is an awesome course to step into ROI driven business analytics fueled by Data Science. In this course, among many other things - he teaches methods to understand and use cheatsheets to gain rapid level-ups, especially to find information connecting various packages and functions and workflows. I have been hooked to this approach and needed a way to quickly refer to the different cheatsheets as needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter notebooks to Org source &#43; Tower of Babel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a simple example demonstrating how a shell script can be called with appropriate variables from any Org file in Emacs. The script essentially converts a Jupyter notebook to Org source, and Babel is leveraged to call the script with appropriate variables from any Org file. This reddit thread and blog post elucidate the advantages of using Babel and Org mode over Jupyter notebooks.
Directly editing code in a Jupyter notebook in a browser is not an attractive long term option and is inconvenient even in the short term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Docker</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/docker-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 14:33:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/docker-notes/</guid>
      <description>Docker is a fascinating concept that could be potentially useful in many ways, especially in Data science, and making reproducible workflows / environments. There are several articles which have great introductions and examples of using docker in data science
This is an evolving summary of my exploration with Docker. It should prove to be a handy refresher of commands and concepts.
TODO What is Docker A brief summary of what Docker is all about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>