<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nteract : An interactive computing environment</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</guid>
      <description>A slide deck from Netflix, mentions using Nteract as their programming notebook, and prompted a mini exploration.
This blog post by Safia Abdalla, (a maintainer/ developer of Nteract) introduces Nteract as an open source, desktop-based, interactive computing application that was designed to overcome a bunch of limitations in Jupyter Notebook&amp;rsquo;s design philosophy. One key difference (among many others) is the ability to execute code in a variety of languages within a single notebook, and it also appears that that the electron based desktop app should make it easier for beginners to start coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter notebooks to Org source &#43; Tower of Babel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/0b63f316-6f6b-4ec2-84a4-5ff287ecf7a7/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a simple example demonstrating how a shell script can be called with appropriate variables from any Org file in Emacs. The script essentially converts a Jupyter notebook to Org source, and Babel is leveraged to call the script with appropriate variables from any Org file. This reddit thread and blog post elucidate the advantages of using Babel and Org mode over Jupyter notebooks.
Directly editing code in a Jupyter notebook in a browser is not an attractive long term option and is inconvenient even in the short term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs notes: Select paragraph and browse-kill-ring for effective content capture</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2d1b3227-28de-4b30-93c8-ad5cbe276e44/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2d1b3227-28de-4b30-93c8-ad5cbe276e44/</guid>
      <description>I like to have any reading material and my notes side by side1. This is easily done with Emacs by splitting the buffer vertically (C-x 3)2
For example: Once a link has been opened via w3m, I hit org-capture (C-c) with a preset template that grabs the URL to the article along with the created date in the properties, with the cursor in position ready to take notes.
(setq org-capture-templates &#39;((&amp;quot;l&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Link + notes&amp;quot; entry (file+headline &amp;quot;~/my_org/link_database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Literate Programming - Emacs, Howard Abrams and Library of Babel</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/6953c104-a8b3-4779-aad3-c33032beb111/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/6953c104-a8b3-4779-aad3-c33032beb111/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an admirer of Howard Abrams, especially because his posts and videos show the awesome power of doing things in Emacs, and the importance of writing clean and logical code. Watching his videos and reading his posts make me feel like I was born yesterday and I am just getting started. But more importantly, they also fire up my imagination regarding the possibilities out there and the potential to create glorious workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An SSD can breathe life into old computers</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/01252410-853f-4570-858f-f3d609f5def5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/01252410-853f-4570-858f-f3d609f5def5/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a well known trick that installing a SSD in place of the conventional Hard disk can breathe new life into very old machines. My mid 2010 Macbook Pro is one such example, being over 8 years old.
In particular, within Emacs - mu4e responds much more quickly and there is significantly less lag in searching / accessing emails and HTML rendering.
The other advantage of using a Mac over Linux is that installation and setup instructions are more often available out the box for the Mac OS (though this is changing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to RSS</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</guid>
      <description>Why use RSS? Off late, I had been relying more on email based content consumption. The phenomenally fast search and filtering capabilities that can be leveraged with mu4e make this easy.
However, even with all these filters, it is quite difficult to keep on top of news from different sources. At times it is inconvenient to mix important emails and correspondence with newsletters and the like, which arrive by the dozen(s) everyday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iosevka - an awesome font for Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</guid>
      <description>Before my foray into Emacs, I purchased applications like IAWriter (classic)1, Marked2, Texts (cross platform Mac/Windows), and have also tried almost all the recommended apps for longer form writing. I am a fan of zen writing apps. In particular the font and environment provided by IAWriter are conducive to focused writing. There also exist apps like Hemingway that also help check the quality of your writing.
Zen writing apps are called so because they have a unique combination of fonts, background color, including line spacing and overall text-width - all of which enable a streamlined and focused flow of words onto the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting productive - an exploration into holistic task management</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To integrate tasks, reminders, notes, coding workflow into a single framework is no easy challenge. Org mode and Emacs help you do just that.
After trying out several tools, IMHO : Todoist offers the best bang for your buck, especially with it&amp;rsquo;s natural language parsing ability, smooth and reliable sync as well as its multi-platform availability. Many describe Omnifocus to be the king of task management tools, with dedicated apps for different purposes and probably well integrated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>