<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>writing on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in writing on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:22:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Iosevka - an awesome font for Emacs</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/951004ce-add0-4e7e-b6e2-2932e0dee429/</guid>
      <description>Before my foray into Emacs, I purchased applications like IAWriter (classic)1, Marked2, Texts (cross platform Mac/Windows), and have also tried almost all the recommended apps for longer form writing. I am a fan of zen writing apps. In particular the font and environment provided by IAWriter are conducive to focused writing. There also exist apps like Hemingway that also help check the quality of your writing.
Zen writing apps are called so because they have a unique combination of fonts, background color, including line spacing and overall text-width - all of which enable a streamlined and focused flow of words onto the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting productive - an exploration into holistic task management</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To integrate tasks, reminders, notes, coding workflow into a single framework is no easy challenge. Org mode and Emacs help you do just that.
After trying out several tools, IMHO : Todoist offers the best bang for your buck, especially with it&amp;rsquo;s natural language parsing ability, smooth and reliable sync as well as its multi-platform availability. Many describe Omnifocus to be the king of task management tools, with dedicated apps for different purposes and probably well integrated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>