<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>documentation | Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/tags/documentation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shreyas.ragavan.co/tags/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>documentation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>documentation</title>
      <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/tags/documentation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributions to the CFD-Online Wiki</title>
      <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/project/cfd-on-line-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/project/cfd-on-line-wiki/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;View : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cfd-online.com/Wiki/What_is_Open_Source%3F&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CFD-Online Wiki page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my initial foray into open source CFD and especially getting
started with Linux - there was a lot of information that I had to
collate from different sources in order to figure out each step. In
addition, there were perspectives on performance that could be gained
only through experience. Therefore, I plugged back the knowledge
gained to the CFD-Online wiki with the idea that it would help any
newbie get started a little quicker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last few years, the number of courses and the material
available on-line on CFD, Linux and applying Numerical techniques has
increased substantially. This is somewhat supported by the increasing
trend of page views &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cfd-online.com/About/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shown on the CFD-Online
Wiki&lt;/a&gt;. Nevertheless, this document
still serves as a useful overview and getting started guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation explores the idea of Open Source software, and the
basic techniques to get started with the exploration. Eg: the
different options of running Linux on your current machine as well as
the pros and cons of each approach, and the software options
available, as well as links to useful and high quality information and
tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
