<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>general | Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/categories/general/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://shreyas.ragavan.co/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>general</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:51:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>general</title>
      <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/categories/general/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental improvements can lead to significant gains</title>
      <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/post/32266f09-c9b9-48ff-9c48-e2348eeda33d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/post/32266f09-c9b9-48ff-9c48-e2348eeda33d/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/a&gt;, I was reflecting that my choice of embracing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Emacs&lt;/a&gt; and progressively gaining mastery over it was intimately connected with the philosophy preached in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My efforts initially started out with a craving for a system to quantify and manage my tasks, habits, notes, blog writing, job applications and projects in a custom environment, and to be able to build toolkits of code to perform repetitive tasks. As mentioned in an &lt;a href=&#34;../2b0b2c79-3f6e-4079-a07d-9e382fda8954&#34;&gt;earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt;
, I tried several approaches before settling on Emacs. The idea was to find or create a single system to track everything of importance in my life (with ease and efficiency). This was instead of a fragmented approach of using multiple tools and techniques, for example, Sublime Text / Atom as a text editor and &lt;a href=&#34;https://todoist.com/?lang=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt; as a task management tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with a vanilla configuration of Emacs and painstakingly borrowed (and eventually) modified lisp snippets to implement desired &amp;lsquo;features&amp;rsquo; or behaviors. It was a just a couple of features every week, initially focused on Org mode&amp;rsquo;s behavior alone. That was nearly 3 years ago. As of now, I am able to manage my blog [hugo], view my email [mu4e], browse the web [w3m], seamlessly capture notes / ideas / tasks from (almost) anywhere [Org mode], chat on IRC, build multi-language code notebooks with ease [Org babel]. All the above provide me significant advantages in speed and efficiency which still have plenty of potential to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, I certainly appear closer to my goal today.. however, I did not know if it was a pipe dream when I started out. It was often extremely frustrating, right from memorizing the &amp;lsquo;crazy&amp;rsquo; keybindings in Emacs, to struggling with getting a lisp snippet to work as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing Emacs had unexpected rewards as well. For example, the need of synchronizing my notes and Emacs configuration with multiple machines led me to Git. &lt;a href=&#34;https://magit.vc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Magit&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; easily accessible commands and relatively visual interface has been a massive help in getting things done with Git, despite not having any deep technical knowledge of how Git works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey with Emacs is testament that an incremental, compounding improvement over time can ultimately result in significant gains. It is also important to acknowledge that I am standing on the shoulder of giants and the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jkitchin/scimax&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scimax&lt;/a&gt; is a cornerstone in my toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to RSS</title>
      <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 07:51:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/post/c641a230-37c9-46aa-84eb-e78cc00d0c7e/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-rss&#34;&gt;Why use RSS?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off late, I had been relying more on email based content consumption. The phenomenally fast search and filtering capabilities that can be leveraged with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djcbsoftware.nl/code/mu/mu4e.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mu4e&lt;/a&gt; make this easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with all these filters, it is quite difficult to keep on top of news and information from different sources. It is actually inconvenient to mix important emails and correspondence with newsletters and the like, which arrive by the dozen(s) everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a nagging feeling that relevant and &amp;lsquo;up to date&amp;rsquo; information is better searched through Google, with a fresh search each time. This approach invites distractions. One remedy is to link a google news feed of a search term into your RSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;, however, the exploration made me actually realise that a dedicated RSS reader could inspire focused reading and aid in retention of information, and could be a better option than flooding my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An all-in-one solution for reading RSS feeds with a capable in-built browser to view images/webpages/videos would be excellent, along with the ability to sync with multiple services and facilitate capturing notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploration&#34;&gt;Exploration:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within Emacs - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skeeto/elfeed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elfeed&lt;/a&gt; (along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/algernon/elfeed-goodies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Elfeed-goodies&lt;/a&gt;) is a good option to read feeds and is strongly integrated with Emacs and org-mode. A single keypress can be programmed to store a link as an org-heading with a note. This would really be my first choice as I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to work rather well. I can use an org file to easily organise my feeds !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there seems no easy way to sync completed feeds to my iOS devices, though &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/areina/elfeed-cljsrn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;solutions exist for Android&lt;/a&gt;. I do spend a lot of time on my computer, however, it seems I can just read better and faster on my iPad and therefore a sync to mobile devices is still important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it does not seem to be a mainstream recommendation on reviews like &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesweetsetup.com/apps/best-rss-reader-os-x/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the sweet setup&lt;/a&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vienna-rss.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt; is a reliable solution (open source!) to consider using to browse RSS feeds on the Mac OS. This comes with a caveat - some tinkering is required to get it to sync with a service.Vienna has inbuilt share options to share via Buffer or Twitter. Side note: I would recommend using &lt;a href=&#34;https://buffer.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buffer&lt;/a&gt; to manage posts on multiple social media sites in a seamless manner. Buffer&amp;rsquo;s free tier should be sufficient for moderate, personal purposes. I use it to post on Twitter and Linked in simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;harvesting-information&#34;&gt;Harvesting information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next consideration was harvesting notable information of interest from the RSS feeds. If not Emacs, the information has to go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.devontechnologies.com/products/devonthink/overview.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DEVONThink Pro&lt;/a&gt; (DTP), which has a handy pull out drawer into which content can be dragged. I was able to just drag and drop the article or text selection into the DTP drawer. This appears as a URL / bookmark in DTP, and can be converted to a formatted note or web archive subsequently. A script could probably accomplish this automatically. That&amp;rsquo;s for a future project.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://shreyas.ragavan.co/img/vienna-dtp-drawer.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Screenshot - Vienna &amp;#43; DTP drawer&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://shreyas.ragavan.co/img/vienna-dtp-drawer.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Screenshot - Vienna + DTP drawer
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Granted, an application external to Emacs (especially without a customisable keyboard driven flow) is not the desirable way to do things. Most websites usually have an RSS feed or email subscription possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opting-for-feedly-as-a-susbcription-service-and-rss-app&#34;&gt;Opting for Feedly as a susbcription service and RSS app&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Vienna had to be abandoned as it felt more sensible to opt for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; subscription to enable a seamless mobile experience. The Feedly app turned out to run surprisingly well on my ancient iPad and I can still drag and drop entire articles into DTP which come out to be formatted RTFD files which could be read and highlighted in leisure. While it may be nice to opt for a standalone app in the Mac for RSS feeds, the Feedly app satisfies my needs and is also available cross-platform. Note: I use the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goldenhillsoftware.com/unread/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Unread app&lt;/a&gt; to read RSS on my newer iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the numerous sync options, &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; provides other interesting features in their pro subscription, like setting up Google keyword searching and organising multiple feeds into &amp;lsquo;boards&amp;rsquo;. This will certainly help in enabling some level of filtering. The method of organising sources and OPML imports in the mac app is a little clunky and not comfortably intuitive, but it is usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://emacs.stackexchange.com/questions/4138/how-do-i-use-emacs-as-a-feedly-com-client&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;no easy way to use Elfeed as a feedly client&lt;/a&gt; either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-cover-them-all&#34;&gt;How to cover them all?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With numerous sources available on most topics - a technique to read is of even more importance. Besides leveraging custom boards, it seems the best way to consume content is to rapidly sweep through the titles and the short descriptions, and in parallel skim through articles of interest. If the article (even slightly) feels worth recording and reading in detail, I select the entire article and drag it into DTP via the drawer for a future session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to deploy DTP as my primary reading app, because of the ability to highlight lines (which are generally available across devices). Besides aiding in skimming the article in the future, it helps me know I&amp;rsquo;ve actually read the article. This is in addition to the core ability to use DTP&amp;rsquo;s AI algorithms in searching through my notes and forming connections between ideas. I also use smart groups that show me the articles captured in the last 1 week, 2 weeks, 3 weeks, which helps me re-visit them in a structured method. The latter works rather well as a memory aid.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://shreyas.ragavan.co/img/feedly-dtp-screenshot.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Article captured from Feedly into DTP&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://shreyas.ragavan.co/img/feedly-dtp-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; &gt;&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Article captured from Feedly into DTP
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans&#34;&gt;Future plans?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be ideal to setup my own server which will process the RSS feeds. Perhaps a Raspberry Pi or something else could be employed. This would be a cost efficient approach for the long term. Such a setup would enable using Elfeed to source articles from the server and thus sync with my mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I guess I will have to rely on Feedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fn-1&#34;&gt;It is probably worth noting that Feedly pro has several 3rd party integrations available out of the box including Evernote.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fn-1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the movie Whiplash</title>
      <link>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://shreyas.ragavan.co/post/5fc69e19-e330-4dd9-9317-7280a9c93966/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whiplash%5F%25282014%5Ffilm%2529&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Whiplash: Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiplash is a fascinating movie on many levels regarding a topic that interests me deeply&amp;hellip; How to progressively perform, and strive to become the very best in a chosen field. Personally, I found each step of the movie riveting and would recommend it to anybody who would find the above question even mildly interesting. The movie&amp;rsquo;s climax  was immensely interesting, inspiring and supported by great acting.  At any rate, the movie induced a blog post !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story revolves around the mind and life of a student who wants to be among the greats in his field, and the way he deals with an abrasive, abusive and unorthodox teacher whose intentions are to bring out the best in a student. No movie is perfect - while some points in Whiplash do appear extreme and therefore relatively unrealistic - the overriding message and theme conveyed certainly rings out clearly, in an engaging plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could relate to the following pointers from the movie:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;leverage-stress-to-achieve-new-levels-of-insight-and-performance&#34;&gt;Leverage stress to achieve new levels of insight and performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The belief of the teacher, that the best performance or attributes hidden inside a person can come out only via repeated, unexpected and  stressful prodding. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this works as shown in the movie, but I have found unexpected insights at times of extreme stress, that have were taken forward to habits that changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;weathering-criticism&#34;&gt;Weathering criticism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mental conditioning required to weather and beat intense, sharp,
depressing criticism along with verbal and physical abuse from a
mentor or teacher and use the same as a motive force for
self-improvement and eventually superlative performance. Though there
are examples of extreme abrasiveness in leaders like Steve Jobs - such
an approach would not be tolerated by most people today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know other stories of people working under such mentors,
striving to learn and gain their approval and eventually winning
the same. These efforts paid off by resulting in skills, thinking
patterns and a superior mental conditioning. Finding such a mentor
at the formative stage is probably the best thing to happen to
anybody.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An effective strategy to find mentors is to shadow people on Linked in and learn from their profiles and activity. Some of them may be willing to connect and invest time in mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another possibility to find like minded people and mentors would be to join the communities of on-line courses, like Datacamp and Dataquest, who have lively channels in Slack for paid members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-back-up-after-a-fall&#34;&gt;Getting back up after a fall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody breaks. Just as the promising student in Whiplash
breaks. But the champions among us rally, to stage a comeback and
performance that make history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regularly surpassing the level of deliberate knowledge of your own performance, and thus improvement by exactly being able to measure your performance and pinpoint mistakes. This point is portrayed in a very interesting manner in Whiplash, where the teacher expects the student to know exactly what mistake is being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;be-great-not-good&#34;&gt;Be Great, not Good&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rejecting the &amp;lsquo;Good&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Good enough&amp;rsquo; feedback from anybody. The goal is to be &lt;em&gt;Great&lt;/em&gt;, not good. The goal should be to strive to set the precedent and not just follow a beaten track. The pinpoint focus should be on progressive improvement to become the best, and that entails never being satisfied and to be ruthless in rooting out flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;achieving-balance-mind-body-surroundings&#34;&gt;Achieving Balance : mind + body + surroundings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great performance is about that perfect balance between the body, mind and environment to leverage the best result possible. I view the scene where the student survives a car crash, just to reach a performance and then not being able to perform, as a good example of overreaching, without strengthening the core, and thus inviting instability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-off-the-beaten-track-and-lose-yourself&#34;&gt;Go off the beaten track and Lose yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the ending of Whiplash that truly drove me to comprehend the points so far. It is twisted, unexpected and led me to truly enjoy the movie and appreciate that: despite the above points being reasonably discernible - the human mind and nature is exceedingly complex. Stability and reasoning are not the only keystones to the foundation of greatness. There has to be a &lt;em&gt;healthy&lt;/em&gt; mix of some form of abnormal obsession thrown in, to make a stellar performance what it is. However, can this be practically repeated on a regular basis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-velocity-and-flow&#34;&gt;Learning velocity and Flow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several bodies of research work available today that can be studied to get closer to consciously stimulating a great performance. One such example is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://unmistakablecreative.com/podcast/unlocking-the-talent-code-with-dan-coyle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Unlocking the Talent Code With Dan Coyle&lt;/a&gt; on the Unmistakable
Creatives podcast provides an insight in line with the points seen
above, into what constitute outliers and performers. The interesting
concept of &amp;lsquo;Learning velocity&amp;rsquo; is explained by Dan with a lucid
example. It is surmised that progress and maximum learning to become
better occurs &lt;em&gt;at&lt;/em&gt; the boundary line dividing what we know at the
moment, and the unknown skills that beckon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That point sems to be an amalgamation of several factors, that are typically present when someone is in &amp;lsquo;flow&amp;rsquo;. Perhaps this flow can be described as a heightened sense of what is, and what should be and the energy to strive and achieve what should be.. It certainly does feel logical to think that we become better by pushing that boundary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
