<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Science on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Science on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ESS for Datascience</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</guid>
      <description>RStudio is a formidable IDE to work with and offers an environment to seamlessly work with multiple languages beyond R. It is especially convenient for tasks involving frequent visualisation of data frames and plots, and for use with Shiny app development.
However, the text (i.e code) editing capabalities are still significantly lacking compared to the likes of Emacs and Vim. Besides this, it does not offer a seamless interface integrating task, time management and multi-language programming environments to the extent available within Org-mode via Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nteract : An interactive computing environment</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/a642fab6-6704-4e57-9f97-43e7dd8d9caa/</guid>
      <description>A slide deck from Netflix, mentions using Nteract as their programming notebook, and prompted a mini exploration.
This blog post by Safia Abdalla, (a maintainer/ developer of Nteract) introduces Nteract as an open source, desktop-based, interactive computing application that was designed to overcome a bunch of limitations in Jupyter Notebook&amp;rsquo;s design philosophy. One key difference (among many others) is the ability to execute code in a variety of languages within a single notebook, and it also appears that that the electron based desktop app should make it easier for beginners to start coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical notes : Research paper on learning/teaching data science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/post/44d30b28-0de8-4211-afad-18fe22323bf3/</guid>
      <description>Title: Navigating Diverse Data Science Learning: Critical Reflections Towards Future Practice
Author: Yehia Elkhatib
Download link
This are my notes on the above paper, which mainly deals with detailing the methods explored and implemented to impart a high quality of education in data science. The paper also provides an interesting breakup of the different roles in data science workflows.
 The importance of being able to work in a team is highlighted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R notes and snippets</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 15:36:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Long &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Wide formats : example for gathering library(&amp;#34;tidyverse&amp;#34;) ## Defining a sample tribble with several duplicates a &amp;lt;- tribble( ~IDS, ~&amp;#34;client id 1&amp;#34;, ~&amp;#34;client id 2&amp;#34;, ~&amp;#34;client id 3&amp;#34;, ~&amp;#34;client id 4&amp;#34;, ~&amp;#34;old app&amp;#34;, ~&amp;#34;new app&amp;#34;, 123, 767, 888,&amp;#34;&amp;#34; , &amp;#34;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;yes&amp;#34; , &amp;#34;no&amp;#34;, 222, 333, 455, 55, 677, &amp;#34;no&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;yes&amp;#34;, 222, 333, 343, 55,677, &amp;#34;no&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;yes&amp;#34; ) ## Defining vector to form column names vec1 &amp;lt;- seq(1:4) vec2 &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;client id&amp;#34; vec3 &amp;lt;- str_glue(&amp;#34;{vec2} {vec1}&amp;#34;) ## Gathering and removing duplicates a %&amp;gt;% gather( key = &amp;#34;Client number&amp;#34;, value = &amp;#34;client ID&amp;#34;, vec3 ) %&amp;gt;% unique() Matrix Defining a matrix A matrix is a collection of elements of the same data type (numeric, character, or logical) arranged into a fixed number of rows and columns.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>