<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data-Science on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data-Science on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ESS for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</guid>
      <description>RStudio is a formidable IDE to work with and offers an environment to seamlessly work with multiple languages beyond R. It is especially convenient for tasks involving frequent visualisation of data frames and plots, and for use with Shiny app development.
However, the text (i.e code) editing capabalities are still significantly lacking compared to the likes of Emacs and Vim. Besides this, it does not offer a seamless interface integrating task, time management and multi-language programming environments to the extent available within Org-mode via Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R notes and snippets</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 14:02:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Lubridate Lubridate: dates and time made easy link. This paper (Grolemund and Wickham) offers a good introduction and comparison between using lubridate and not using it, as well as several examples of using the library. It also offers some case studies which can serve as useful drill exercises.
Importing multiple excel sheet from multiple excel files This is one approach to importing multiple sheets from multiple excel files into a list of tibbles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>