<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Shreyas Ragavan</title>
    <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Shreyas Ragavan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shrysr.github.io/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ESS for Data Science</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/ess-datascience-r/</guid>
      <description>RStudio is a formidable IDE to work with and offers an environment to seamlessly work with multiple languages beyond R. It is especially convenient for tasks involving frequent visualisation of data frames and plots, and for use with Shiny app development.
However, the text (i.e code) editing capabalities are still significantly lacking compared to the likes of Emacs and Vim. Besides this, it does not offer a seamless interface integrating task, time management and multi-language programming environments to the extent available within Org-mode via Emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Docker</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/docker-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 14:33:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/docker-notes/</guid>
      <description>Docker is a fascinating concept that could be potentially useful in many ways, especially in Data science, and making reproducible workflows / environments. There are several articles which have great introductions and examples of using docker in data science
This is an evolving summary of my exploration with Docker. It should prove to be a handy refresher of commands and concepts.
TODO What is Docker A brief summary of what Docker is all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R notes and snippets</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 11:21:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/r-notes-snippets/</guid>
      <description>Lubridate - introductory technical paper This paper (Grolemund and Wickham) offers a good introduction and comparison between using lubridate and not using it, as well as several examples of using the library. It also offers some case studies which can serve as useful drill exercises.
Importing multiple excel sheets from multiple excel files This is one approach to importing multiple sheets from multiple excel files into a list of tibbles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Emacs &#43; Scimax configuration</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/sr-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 13:55:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/sr-config/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is my literate, Org-mode based configuration for Emacs, which are essentially customisations built on top of the starter-kit Scimax. View a nicely rendered version with easy navigation on my website, or if you prefer: on github.
 Scimax - Awesome editing for scientists and engineers. Scimax is an Emacs starterkit for scientists and engineers. It provides a comprehensive configuration of Emacs for scientific programming and publishing.
John Kitchin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux notes</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/linux-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 19:53:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/linux-notes/</guid>
      <description>Installing the Iosevka font On Debian distros There appear to be no packages for iosevka for debian. The prescribed method is to add the fonts to the fonts folder. The github issues point towards a PPA which can be added. However, this did not work for me, and I had to resort to manual means.
Downloading the specified font version from github into a temp folder
cd ~/temp wget &amp;#34;https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB and NoSQL Databases</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/nosql-mongodb-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 12:12:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/nosql-mongodb-notes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction These are my notes on NoSQL databases and the prime differences between them and SQL databases. The notes are mostly based off the Udemy course Introduction to MongoDB, and therefore primarily focused on using MongoDB at the moment.
Methodology and Tools Installing Mongodb The instructions are available in the mongoDB manual. This is for the Community edition, and on a Mac as welll as Linux machine (Antergos)
Mac If never installed before, tap the resource first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>quotes</title>
      <link>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 11:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shrysr.github.io/docs/quotes/</guid>
      <description>“I never made one of my discoveries through the process of rational thinking” ― Albert Einstein “To be fully alive, fully human, and completely awake is to be continually thrown out of the nest. To live fully is to be always in no-man’s-land, to experience each moment as completely new and fresh. To live is to be willing to die over and over again. ” ― Pema Chödrön, When Things Fall Apart: Heart Advice for Difficult Times Perfectionism can’t survive unless it is fed with the oxygen of indulgence and paranoia and irrationality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>